<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Skin Peel - Blog</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/skin-peel/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>My WordPress Blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 11:10:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Is Lip Filler Injections</title>
		<link>/2023/03/22/is-lip-filler-injections/</link>
					<comments>/2023/03/22/is-lip-filler-injections/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mhiz Maryam Maryam]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 11:10:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Skin Peel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cosmeticsenvogue.com/?p=11043</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Is Lip Filler Injections? are a popular cosmetic procedure. There are two types of injectables – temporary fillers and permanent fillers. The first type is to be used for a short period of time, the second may need to be repeated, in order to provide a long term result, Lip fillers, also known as lip...</p>
<p>The post <a href="/2023/03/22/is-lip-filler-injections/">Is Lip Filler Injections</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Is Lip Filler Injections? are a popular cosmetic procedure. There are two types of injectables – temporary fillers and permanent fillers. The first type is to be used for a short period of time, the second may need to be repeated, in order to provide a long term result, Lip fillers, also known as lip augmentation, are non-surgical injectables. They are used to change the shape and volume of lips. The substances can be placed in different parts of lips depending on the results desired. It has been stated that lip fillers injection is much safer than surgery! In fact, since they do not involve any use of cutting equipment or anaesthesia, the procedure is always performed with no informed consent from the person.</p>



<p>Lip filler injections, or dermal fillers as they are also known, can be used to enhance the lips, reduce fine lines and wrinkles around the mouth, or lift sagging areas of the face. Proven popular across many decades, these dermal fillers are now available in a number of formulations depending on your specific needs. The most popular formulation as it pertains to lips is hyaluronic acid (HA) fillers such as Restylane and Juvederm. There are many different varieties available with varying longevity of effects.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://cosmeticsenvogue.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/image-1529.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11056" width="438" height="292" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Is Lip Filler Injections</h2>



<p>Lip filler injections are a cosmetic procedure that plumps up the lips and gives them a fuller appearance.</p>



<p>The main ingredients used in lip filler injections include hyaluronic acid and collagen. These substances are naturally present in the body and help your skin look full and healthy.</p>



<p>Lip filler injections can be used to correct certain types of lip defects, such as when lips are too thin or asymmetrical. They can also be used for cosmetic purposes, such as making lips appear more voluptuous.</p>



<p>Lip filler injections are effective because they stimulate the production of collagen and hyaluronic acid in the skin. This leads to an increase in volume and fullness, which is what causes lips to become plumper after treatment. The effects last between 6 months and 2 years, depending on how much volume has been added by the injected material.</p>



<p>Lip filler injections are a great way to enhance your lips. It&#8217;s important to choose a professional who is not only skilled, but also knowledgeable about the latest techniques and technologies.</p>



<p>There are several different types of lip fillers on the market today:</p>



<p>Hyaluronic Acid (HA) Fillers &#8211; These are the most commonly used injectable materials for lip enhancement. HA fillers last approximately 6-12 months before they begin to break down and lose their effectiveness. They can be combined with BOTOX for more dramatic results.</p>



<p>Sculptra® Aesthetic &#8211; This is an injectable medicine that&#8217;s approved by the FDA for improving facial volume in adults who have lost fat from their cheeks or smile lines. Sculptra Aesthetic can last up to two years, but its effects may vary depending on your individual situation.</p>



<p>Fat Transfer &#8211; Fat transfer involves taking fat from one part of your body and transferring it to another part (such as your lips). Fat transfer works well if you have enough excess fat available in other areas of your body where it will be safe to remove, such as the abdomen or thighs.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Are cosmetic dermal fillers safe?" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fs84LBZPCy8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Can Lip Fillers Cause Cancer</h2>



<p>Lip injections are a popular procedure that can give lips a fuller, more youthful appearance. The most commonly used filler is hyaluronic acid, which is also used in many other cosmetic procedures.</p>



<p>The American Society of Plastic Surgeons (ASPS) reports that the number of lip injections increased by more than 100% from 2015 to 2016. Lip fillers help improve the appearance of thin and sagging lips. They also can correct injuries that have left a scar on your lower lip or upper lip area.</p>



<p>Lip filler injections may be a good option for you if you:</p>



<p>Have thinning or loss of volume in your upper or lower lip area</p>



<p>Want fullness to balance an uneven smile line</p>



<p>Are unhappy with the natural shape of your lips after weight loss or facial surgery such as rhinoplasty (nose reshaping).</p>



<p>Lip augmentation, also known as lip filler injections, is a cosmetic procedure that involves the injection of hyaluronic acid into the lips. This makes them fuller, plumper and more voluptuous.</p>



<p>The procedure can be done by a trained professional in just 15 minutes. The results last for up to 18 months and may be permanent with repeated treatments.</p>



<p>The most common side effect of lip augmentation is bruising that lasts several days after treatment. Other possible side effects include swelling and redness around the lips and nosebleeds due to bruising in the nose area. Your doctor will discuss these risks with you before treatment begins, </p>



<p>Lip fillers are a popular cosmetic treatment. They can help give your lips a fuller and more defined look. But, it’s important to be aware of the possible risks of lip filler injections.</p>



<p>It’s important to note that there is no conclusive evidence that links lip fillers with cancer. However, there have been reports of people developing cancer in their lips after getting injected with hyaluronic acid (HA) fillers.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://cosmeticsenvogue.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/image-1530.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11059" width="406" height="271" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Lip Fillers Near Me</h2>



<p>Lip filler injection is a cosmetic procedure to enhance the lips. Lip fillers are used to increase the volume of the lips, create more definition, and correct uneven lip shape.</p>



<p>Lip filler injections are also known as dermal fillers or soft tissue augmentation. Dermal fillers can be used to correct facial deformities and scars, as well as for lip augmentation and correction of age-related loss of volume in the face.</p>



<p>In this procedure, a small amount of an injectable filler material is injected into the lips using a fine needle. The material creates an immediate temporary improvement in the appearance of your lips by adding fullness and volume.</p>



<p>Lip filler injections are an excellent way to enhance the appearance of your lips. These injections can add fullness to your lips and make them look more youthful and attractive. Lip filler injections can also be used to create a more defined lip line, which can make it easier for you to apply lipstick.</p>



<p>The best candidates for lip filler injections are people who have naturally thin lips or those who desire fuller looking lips. However, if you smoke cigarettes or drink alcohol regularly, these products may not work as well for you because they can cause your skin to become thinner over time.</p>



<p>In addition to enhancing the appearance of your lips, lip fillers near me can also help improve other facial features such as wrinkles around the corners of your mouth, which is known as the nasolabial fold. Another benefit associated with these products is that they provide instant results that last for several months before needing another injection</p><p>The post <a href="/2023/03/22/is-lip-filler-injections/">Is Lip Filler Injections</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2023/03/22/is-lip-filler-injections/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is Face Fillers Bad</title>
		<link>/2023/03/22/is-face-fillers-bad/</link>
					<comments>/2023/03/22/is-face-fillers-bad/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Ajay Emancipate]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 10:59:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Skin Peel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cosmeticsenvogue.com/?p=11049</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>What is face fillers? Face fillers are substances that are injected into the skin to add volume. They can be made up of collagen, hyaluronic acid, and other biocompatible materials. The purpose of this treatment is to add volume or fullness to areas of the face that have lost fat or elasticity. How does it...</p>
<p>The post <a href="/2023/03/22/is-face-fillers-bad/">Is Face Fillers Bad</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>What is face fillers? Face fillers are substances that are injected into the skin to add volume. They can be made up of collagen, hyaluronic acid, and other biocompatible materials. The purpose of this treatment is to add volume or fullness to areas of the face that have lost fat or elasticity.</p>



<p>How does it help? This procedure can help reduce the appearance of fine lines and wrinkles around the lips, cheeks, jawline and around the eyes. It also helps to improve a sunken appearance caused by age related loss in facial volume. It&#8217;s often used as an alternative to surgery because it offers similar results but with less downtime and discomfort.</p>



<p>Read on to learn more about Is Face Fillers Bad Do Fillers Ruin Your FaceFrightened of Fillers?</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://api.ellecanada.com/app/uploads/2020/04/WebFillers.jpg" alt="webfillers" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Is Face Fillers Bad</h2>



<p>When people make appointments with qualified medical practitioners to get fillers, there’s usually only one “after” they’re picturing: smoother, plumper skin. For the most part, this is what they get. But when patients sit down in Dr. Mike Roskies’ office for their first appointment, they’re presented with a long list of other, less desirable after-effects, too.</p>



<p>Roskies is a facial plastic and reconstructive surgeon and the medical director of SpaMedica in Toronto. In an ordinary, non-quarantined week, he sees about 25 to 100 patients for injectable fillers, and patients range in age from their teens to their eighties. Each patient gets “The Talk” about what to expect when they leave Roskies’ office. He says thanks to Instagram and other social channels, the taboo around getting these procedures has been lowered and the results overexposed to such a degree that people approach fillers a little too casually, without considering the aftereffects. “People need to treat this like a medical procedure with a medical risk; it’s not like going for a manicure,” he says.&nbsp;</p>



<p>While people used to wait until they saw visible signs of aging to act, many in their late twenties and early thirties are now hitting up doctors’ offices as a preventative measure. Roskies says most people want to enhance what they’ve already got instead of&nbsp;trying to build whole new features. For the most part, people are using&nbsp;hyaluronic acid&nbsp;fillers, the same component found in many topical skin care products designed for anti-aging and skin plumping.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There are, however, three categories of filler: permanent, semi-permanent, and non-permanent. The one you choose affects your outcome. Permanent fillers are made of silicone. Though silicone is safe for procedures like breast augmentation, Roskies says clients should steer clear of it for anything related to the face because anything that goes awry is not easily fixable. Semi-permanent fillers are made out of products like Sculptra, which stimulates collagen production in the injected area. While the filler itself doesn’t stay in your system, its effects last a lifetime. Hyaluronic acid, on the other hand, is non-permanent. Composed of a sugar molecule which is also produced naturally in the body, it generally dissolves and is excreted by the body in six to nine months. And if a client wants to get rid of it sooner, the area can be injected with an enzyme which will dissolve the filler completely within two hours.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Aging won’t be accelerated once you stop using filler.”</p>



<p>Due to the low-maintenance factor of most fillers on the market, some of the worst fears people have about longterm use of filler are unfounded. Many of Roskies’ patients, for example, worry that they won’t be able to simply stop getting fillers. They’re afraid that, over time, their skin will sag after receiving filler and they’ll be tied to injections for life. Roskies says this isn’t a concern with hyaluronic acid fillers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Another major worry people have is that they won’t be able to stop using fillers cold turkey because their signs of aging will be exacerbated. Roskies says it’s safe to get an injection and never have a followup appointment. “Aging won’t be accelerated once you stop using filler,” Roskies says. “But I joke with my patients that as soon as you leave my office, you’re going to start aging again. Gravity spends all of its time with you, and I spend 30 minutes with you.”</p>



<p>Dr. Patricia Wexler, celebrity dermatologist at Wexler Dermatology in New York,&nbsp;warns that there is such a thing as overdoing it with filler: in time, repeated injections can make the face look unnatural, which may not be the desired effect. That said, many people who are pleased with the results of their fillers opt to go for follow-up appointments once the acid dissolves and its effects wear off. Wexler says the time span between appointments will depend on the area of injection, the age of the client, and the state of their skin to begin with, among other factors. Generally, she says, younger people may find hyaluronic acid injections last about a year, while older folks may want to come for touch-ups every four to six months. Most of Roskies’ patients come back within six to nine.</p>



<p>“I joke with my patients that as soon as you leave my office, you’re going to start aging again. Gravity spends all of its time with you, and I spend 30 minutes with you.”</p>



<p>“As we get older we have less collagen support, less elasticity, so it’s not going to hold as long,” Wexler says. For those of us who can’t make our follow-ups for whatever reason – say, a global pandemic that prevents us from leaving the house – practicing good skincare in the interim can go a long way. Roskies says people’s skin routines should always be custom-created for them depending on skin type, sun exposure, age, and pollution contact, but he recommends using retinol, vitamin C, and sunblock for optimal care.</p>



<p>Wexler says there’s not a lot of mystery to fillers at this point, and doctors are aware of any risks that could crop up —&nbsp; with the exception, of course, of new products hitting the market.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sidestepping unwanted side effects, in the meantime, takes research and finding the right practitioner. Both Wexler and Roskies say providers of these services should always warn patients of any aftereffects they might experience, beyond the desired ones. Both see people for follow-up appointments and provide advice for aftercare, as well as for any emergency care.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“You should always feel like there’s a safety net,” says Roskies. “It should never be that you see somebody in their basement for fillers, leave, and that’s it.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Protect Yourself from Facial Injection Disfigurement" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5ccHkjfEWbw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Do Fillers Ruin Your Face</h2>



<p>Fillers are injections made with hyaluronic acid or calcium hydroxylapatite. Both are compounds that occur naturally in your body, but the filler is usually made from lab-grown cells that have been cultivated to produce more of the substance.</p>



<p>The results can be dramatic and long-lasting, but not everyone is a good candidate for this treatment. You should also know that fillers can be dangerous if not administered properly.</p>



<p>One of the biggest risks is infection, which can cause disfigurement or even death if left untreated. Other side effects include pain, bruising and swelling at the injection site.</p>



<p>There are many different types of fillers on the market today, including Restylane, Juvederm and Radiesse among others. However, you should always ask your physician which one they recommend for your particular needs before agreeing to any procedure.</p>



<p>Some people think that fillers will give them a more youthful appearance by smoothing out wrinkles and folds in their skin, but this isn&#8217;t always true because they don&#8217;t actually change how much collagen or elastin is produced by the body&#8217;s natural processes — they just add more volume to certain areas so they look fuller than they are naturally</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Frightened of Fillers?</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://cdn.sanity.io/images/iy559jeo/production/d6a08f264ba9fc669ee4087c25b3a07607b517b1-768x768.jpg?w=320&amp;auto=format&amp;dpr=2" alt="" /></figure>



<p></p>



<p>Speak to any woman who hasn&#8217;t had fillers and we&#8217;re all terrified of fillers. More so than Botox. Fillers have become feared because we see too may photos of celebrities who have had too much and turned into puffed-up versions of themselves, with eyes sinking to the back of their heads, and an inability to produce any kind of expression &#8211; I know what you think, anyone who has fillers ends up looking like Joan Rivers!</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Do Fillers Ruin Your Face?</h3>



<p>With such negativity around&nbsp;dermal fillers, it seems like it should be a no-go treatment. I&#8217;m pretty sure most of us just discount it immediately as we don&#8217;t quite believe that it won&#8217;t make us look insane. I know it&#8217;s true as I had the very conversation with a Mum mate at the school gates. We got chatting about ageing, feeling haggard, looking tired and Botox and fillers. She knows I work with Glowday and asked me what would help with her hollow eyes and jowls. Now, I&#8217;m no medical pro but I know enough that dermal fillers could be one potential option. Her nose scrunched up and she made a &#8216;mmmmmm&#8217; sound and then said; &#8216;But they&#8217;re bad aren&#8217;t they? You end up looking fake and weird &#8211; everyone would know &#8211; I&#8217;d look worse than I do now&#8217;.</p>



<p></p><p>The post <a href="/2023/03/22/is-face-fillers-bad/">Is Face Fillers Bad</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2023/03/22/is-face-fillers-bad/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is Eyelid Lift Surgery Dangerous</title>
		<link>/2023/03/22/is-eyelid-lift-surgery-dangerous/</link>
					<comments>/2023/03/22/is-eyelid-lift-surgery-dangerous/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Ajay Emancipate]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 10:55:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Skin Peel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cosmeticsenvogue.com/?p=11048</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>For many people, eyelid surgery is a way to look younger and more refreshed. But before you jump in to this type of procedure, you should know that it can be dangerous. Eyelid lift surgery is performed in an outpatient setting under general anesthesia. The procedure takes about three hours to complete. The surgeon makes...</p>
<p>The post <a href="/2023/03/22/is-eyelid-lift-surgery-dangerous/">Is Eyelid Lift Surgery Dangerous</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For many people, eyelid surgery is a way to look younger and more refreshed. But before you jump in to this type of procedure, you should know that it can be dangerous.</p>



<p>Eyelid lift surgery is performed in an outpatient setting under general anesthesia. The procedure takes about three hours to complete. The surgeon makes incisions in the natural creases of your upper eyelids and removes excess fat and tissue from beneath them. The surgeon then repositions the excess skin and tissue in order to give you a more youthful appearance by lifting your brows, reducing sagging skin and smoothing out wrinkles around your eyes.</p>



<p> Read on to learn more about Is Eyelid Lift Surgery Dangerous, Cost Of Eyelid Surgery How to Relieve Pain After Eyelid Surgery</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Is Eyelid Lift Surgery Dangerous</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://contoura.com/assets/img/blog/eyelid-surgery-safe.jpg" alt="Featured Image" /></figure>



<p><strong>What is Eyelid Surgery?</strong></p>



<p>Eyelid surgery is a procedure to reduce the drooping or bagging of the upper or lower eyelids. Called&nbsp;blepharoplasty, the procedure is often done for cosmetic reasons. It can, however, become medically necessary if the drooping skin begins to obstruct vision.</p>



<p>As you age, your skin changes, including your eyelids. The supporting muscles may weaken while the skin stretches. The combination allows fat to accumulate either above or below the eyes.</p>



<p>The result can be the appearance of bags beneath the eyes, the drooping of eyelids and eyebrows, and excess skin around the eyes. It can even make your eyes look puffy.</p>



<p>The eyelid lift procedure is not a dangerous procedure, but there are some risks involved. The most common side effects are bruising, swelling and numbness. These side effects will generally go away within a week.</p>



<p>The most severe risk of eyelid lift surgery is that the patient may have difficulties seeing for several weeks after the procedure. This risk can be minimized by using an antibiotic ointment and avoiding any strenuous activity for 24 hours after the surgery.</p>



<p>Eyelid lift surgery should not be performed on patients who have uncontrolled high blood pressure or bleeding disorders such as hemophilia or von Willebrand&#8217;s disease. Patients who have diabetes or thyroid disease may also be at greater risk than other patients because these conditions can cause complications during the operation itself.</p>



<p>Patients who smoke should not undergo an eyelid lift because smoking increases their chance of developing eye problems later on in life (such as cataracts).</p>



<p>Many people are concerned about eyelid surgery but it is a safe, effective procedure. The risks associated with an eyelid lift are small and very rare.</p>



<p>Eyelid lift surgery is a minor procedure that is performed under local anesthesia and usually requires no overnight stay in hospital. The procedure usually takes less than an hour but may occasionally take longer depending on the nature of your particular case.</p>



<p>Eyelid lift surgery involves making tiny incisions in the natural crease above each eye. Tissue is gently pulled forward and excess skin is removed to create a more youthful appearance. The incision sites are then closed with dissolvable sutures, which will dissolve over time without leaving any scars behind (depending on your choice).</p>



<p>Some patients might experience some swelling around the eyes after their procedure but this should go away within a few days after surgery. You should also avoid rubbing or touching your eyes for at least two weeks following your eyelid lift so that you don&#8217;t cause any unnecessary damage to the newly formed scar tissue while it&#8217;s healing.</p>



<p>While there are no guarantees when it comes to results from any type of cosmetic procedure, most patients who undergo an eyelid lift experience noticeable improvements in their appearance within just a few days after their</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Is the surgery covered by Medicare and private health funds" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sR4kg8sbRz0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Cost Of Eyelid Surgery</h2>



<p>Blepharoplasty is cosmetic surgery of the eyelid in which excessive eyelid skin is removed with or without the removal or addition of eyelid fat.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Blepharoplasty&nbsp;is&nbsp;cosmetic surgery&nbsp;of the&nbsp;eyelid&nbsp;in which excessive eyelid skin is removed with or without the removal or addition of eyelid fat.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The term blepharoplasty was coined by the German ophthalmologist, von Graefe in 1818 to describe eyelid repair surgery. The word ‘blepharoplasty’ is derived from the Greek blepharon, meaning ‘eyelid’, and plastos, meaning ‘formed’.</p>



<p>It is commonly referred to as eyelid lift. However, the term is a misnomer as the eyelid is not actually ‘lifted’ during the procedure. Blepharoplasty is one of the most common cosmetic surgical procedures of the face. It is performed more often in women than in men, most commonly in their fifties.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Blepharoplasty typically costs a little over $3,000 for the surgery alone, not counting anesthesia and related hospital expenses, according to the latest data.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">How can upper eyelid surgery help me?</h3>



<p>Blepharoplasty can be done for functional reasons when eyelid folds interfere with normal vision or health of the eye or for cosmetic reasons. The indications include:</p>



<ul>
<li>Tired looking or baggy eyes</li>



<li>Droopy eyelids</li>



<li>Excess skin on the upper eyelid that interferes with vision</li>



<li>Age-related cosmetic changes of the eyelid</li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Are there any medical alternatives to eyelid surgery?</h3>



<p>The excess skin and fat of the upper eyelid cannot be corrected by medication. However, in patients with severe functional deficits in visual fields who are not fit for surgery, spectacles with a&nbsp;ptosis&nbsp;crutch or taping up of the excess skin may provide some temporary improvement.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Is eyelid surgery safe?</h3>



<p>With a skilled surgeon, proper planning, and good patient selection, the surgery usually turns out to be a quick, simple and low-risk procedure. Nonetheless, like any surgery there are potential complications, including:</p>



<p>Bleeding&nbsp;</p>



<p>Infection&nbsp;</p>



<p>Hematoma&nbsp;collection of blood under the eyelid)</p>



<p>Loss of vision</p>



<p>Raised eyeball pressure&nbsp;</p>



<p>Pain&nbsp;</p>



<p>Scarring</p>



<p>Lid lag</p>



<p>Insufficient drooping correction</p>



<p>Diplopia&nbsp;(double vision)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Asymmetric or unequal eyelid creases</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How to Relieve Pain After Eyelid Surgery</h2>



<p>Depending on the circumstances, your doctor may prescribe pain relievers and anti-inflammatory drugs within the first few days after surgery.</p>



<p>Beware though, that not all pain medications are safe. Some drugs, such as ibuprofen and aspirin,&nbsp;may increase bleeding&nbsp;and affect recovery. Don’t take any medications without your doctor’s approval.</p>



<p>For every hour on the night after the procedure, you may need to apply ice packs or cold compresses on your eyes. This helps reduce pain and swelling.</p>



<p>Makeup products, eye serums, face creams, and other cosmetics contain chemicals that may damage the skin around your eyes; Avoid them for two weeks or so. If you wash your hair, make sure to keep water, shampoo, and soap out of your eyes.</p>



<p>Your doctor may also recommend antibiotic ointments and eye drops. Use them as prescribed. These medications prevent infections and ensure a smooth recovery.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Give Your Eyes a Well-Deserved Break</h2>



<p>Your body needs time to fix damaged tissues. That’s why it’s recommended to get plenty of sleep and follow a balanced diet after the intervention.</p>



<p>Also, take some time off from exercising and doing house chores. Your doctor will likely recommend avoiding heavy lifting, high-impact aerobics, jogging, and other intense activities for around a week.</p>



<p>Stop smoking and limit your exposure in the first few weeks after surgery. Don’t drive until you’re no longer taking any narcotics and/or other pain relievers.</p>



<p>Refrain from using the computer, reading, and watching TV for more than a couple of minutes, as your eyes will get tired easily.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Get Rid of Sagging Eyelids and Feel Like Yourself Again</h2>



<p>Now that you know what to do after eyelid surgery, it’s time to decide whether the procedure is right for you. Discuss your options with a&nbsp;qualified surgeon. Don’t be afraid to ask questions so you know what to expect before, during, and after the procedure.</p>



<p>Pain is part of the recovery process. If you follow the doctor’s recommendations, you should feel better within a few days.</p><p>The post <a href="/2023/03/22/is-eyelid-lift-surgery-dangerous/">Is Eyelid Lift Surgery Dangerous</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2023/03/22/is-eyelid-lift-surgery-dangerous/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is Microdermabrasion Better Than A Chemical Peel</title>
		<link>/2023/03/22/is-microdermabrasion-better-than-a-chemical-peel/</link>
					<comments>/2023/03/22/is-microdermabrasion-better-than-a-chemical-peel/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mhiz Maryam Maryam]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 09:40:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Skin Peel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cosmeticsenvogue.com/?p=11018</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Is Microdermabrasion Better Than A Chemical Peel Microdermabrasion is a procedure that uses small crystals to resurface the skin and improve its appearance. A chemical peel, on the other hand, uses chemicals to remove the outer layer of skin. Both procedures can make you look younger and healthier by reducing wrinkles and fine lines., Microdermabrasion...</p>
<p>The post <a href="/2023/03/22/is-microdermabrasion-better-than-a-chemical-peel/">Is Microdermabrasion Better Than A Chemical Peel</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Is Microdermabrasion Better Than A Chemical Peel</p>



<p>Microdermabrasion is a procedure that uses small crystals to resurface the skin and improve its appearance. A chemical peel, on the other hand, uses chemicals to remove the outer layer of skin. Both procedures can make you look younger and healthier by reducing wrinkles and fine lines., Microdermabrasion is getting more popular because of the benefits it provides when compared to a chemical peel. This article explores some of the benefits of microdermabrasion that makes it better than a chemical peel.</p>



<p>Microdermabrasion and chemical peels are two of the most common facial procedures, but what&#8217;s important to know is that they are very different, and each is best suited for some clients over others. So, which one is better? Is microdermabrasion better than a chemical peel.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://cosmeticsenvogue.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/image-1524.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11027" width="443" height="295" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Is Microdermabrasion Better Than A Chemical Peel</h2>



<p>Microdermabrasion is a type of skin treatment that uses tiny crystals to gently remove the top layer of skin. It can be used to treat fine lines, acne scars and sun damage.</p>



<p>Chemical peels use acids or other chemicals to remove layers of skin. They can also be used to treat fine lines, acne scars and sun damage.</p>



<p>There are similarities between microdermabrasion and chemical peels. Both can improve your complexion by removing dead skin cells from the surface of your face. Both have their pros and cons — for example, chemical peels are usually more effective at combating wrinkles than microdermabrasion but may cause more irritation.</p>



<p>Microdermabrasion is a process that uses crystals to gently remove dead skin and dirt. It can be done in a doctor&#8217;s office or at home with an at-home kit. Microdermabrasion is often used as a skin treatment to help improve the appearance of the skin, such as:</p>



<p>Reduce fine lines and wrinkles</p>



<p>Fade age spots</p>



<p>Even out uneven pigmentation (brown spots) caused by sun exposure</p>



<p>Microdermabrasion is not a substitute for professional medical treatment, but it can be used before or after surgery to help the healing process. It may also be used as part of your daily skincare routine, depending on your needs.</p>



<p>Microdermabrasion is a popular skin care treatment that can be used on the face, neck and chest. It&#8217;s a safe, noninvasive procedure that removes dead skin cells, helping to make the skin look brighter and healthier.</p>



<p>Microdermabrasion works by using a handheld wand or machine to gently buff away the top layers of dead skin cells. The process is similar to exfoliating with a scrub or loofah, except that it&#8217;s done in a controlled manner by an aesthetician or dermatologist with specialized training in this type of procedure.</p>



<p>Is Microdermabrasion Better Than A Chemical Peel?</p>



<p>Microdermabrasion is one of several types of facial resurfacing treatments used by dermatologists and aestheticians. It&#8217;s often used as part of your regular skin care regimen (usually once or twice per month) in place of chemical peels, which are more invasive and require more recovery time afterward.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Microdermabrasion vs Chemical Peel" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UvkNGOvYwyo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Microdermabrasion And Chemical Peel Together</h2>



<p>Microdermabrasion is a gentle, non-invasive procedure that exfoliates the outer layer of skin to remove dead skin cells and reveal new, healthy skin. It&#8217;s also sometimes referred to as microdermabrade or microderm.</p>



<p>A chemical peel is a procedure where chemicals are applied to the face to cause controlled damage to the top layer of skin, which then sheds and reveals newer, fresher skin underneath. The goal is to improve acne scars and sun damage, as well as help prevent wrinkles and fine lines.</p>



<p>Microdermabrasion and chemical peels are both used for different reasons and have different effects on your skin. Neither treatment is better than the other; they&#8217;re just different ways to achieve similar results in your skincare routine.</p>



<p>Microdermabrasion and chemical peels are often used together in a series of treatments. This combination can provide a wide range of benefits for your skin, but it&#8217;s important to know what each treatment does before deciding if they&#8217;re right for you.</p>



<p>Microdermabrasion</p>



<p>Microdermabrasion is a nonsurgical procedure that uses small crystals to gently exfoliate the skin. These crystals are applied directly onto the skin and then vacuumed off. This process can be repeated until you&#8217;ve achieved the desired results.</p>



<p>Microdermabrasion is primarily used for fine lines, wrinkles, acne scars and dark spots on the face. It&#8217;s also useful for brightening dull-looking skin and removing sun damage from the face or body.</p>



<p>Chemical Peel</p>



<p>A chemical peel uses various chemicals to remove dead skin cells from your face or body in order to reveal new layers of healthy skin underneath. The chemicals may irritate your skin slightly while they&#8217;re working, but they shouldn&#8217;t cause too much discomfort overall unless you have sensitive skin or an allergy to certain substances like benzoyl peroxide or salicylic acid (which are two common ingredients found in many over-the-counter peels).</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://cosmeticsenvogue.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/image-1523.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11025" width="452" height="237" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Chemical Peel Vs Microdermabrasion Cost</h2>



<p>Microdermabrasion and chemical peels are both skin treatments that exfoliate the top layer of skin, but they work in different ways.</p>



<p>Microdermabrasion is a mechanical process that uses a rotating brush to remove the dead cells from your face. It can be done at home or at the dermatologist&#8217;s office. Microdermabrasion can be used on all skin types, but it&#8217;s typically recommended for people with oily or acne-prone skin because it helps reduce pore size and improve texture.</p>



<p>Chemical peels use chemicals to remove dead skin cells from your face. These treatments are typically done by a dermatologist or aesthetician and can help treat fine lines, wrinkles, acne scars and discoloration. There are several types of chemical peels, including glycolic acid peels, salicylic acid peels and trichloroacetic acid (TCA) peels.</p>



<p>Microdermabrasion is a non-surgical procedure that is used to improve skin texture, reduce fine lines and wrinkles, decrease pore size, and treat acne scars.</p>



<p>Microdermabrasion works by using a mechanical exfoliation device to gently remove the top layer of dead skin cells. This process exposes new healthy skin cells that have been waiting underneath all along.</p>



<p>Chemical peels are chemical solutions applied to the skin to improve its appearance and texture. Chemical peels are typically used for deep resurfacing of the skin with light to deep chemical exfoliation, which may include removal of sun damage, fine lines, wrinkles, and acne scarring.</p>



<p>A chemical peel will usually result in more significant changes in your skin than microdermabrasion because it removes more layers of your outermost skin layer (epidermis). This allows for deeper exfoliation than microdermabrasion does on its own since it only removes a small amount of epidermis at a time.</p><p>The post <a href="/2023/03/22/is-microdermabrasion-better-than-a-chemical-peel/">Is Microdermabrasion Better Than A Chemical Peel</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2023/03/22/is-microdermabrasion-better-than-a-chemical-peel/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is Microdermabrasion The Same As A Chemical Peel</title>
		<link>/2023/03/22/is-microdermabrasion-the-same-as-a-chemical-peel/</link>
					<comments>/2023/03/22/is-microdermabrasion-the-same-as-a-chemical-peel/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mhiz Maryam Maryam]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 09:33:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Skin Peel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cosmeticsenvogue.com/?p=11008</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Is Microdermabrasion The Same As A Chemical Peel _ are both facial rejuvenation treatments that help to clear up the skin. From their description, these two cosmetic treatments may sound similar, but the reality is they&#8217;re quite different, Microdermabrasion is a skin resurfacing treatment that uses gentle abrasion to improve the appearance of uneven skin...</p>
<p>The post <a href="/2023/03/22/is-microdermabrasion-the-same-as-a-chemical-peel/">Is Microdermabrasion The Same As A Chemical Peel</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Is Microdermabrasion The Same As A Chemical Peel _ are both facial rejuvenation treatments that help to clear up the skin. From their description, these two cosmetic treatments may sound similar, but the reality is they&#8217;re quite different, Microdermabrasion is a skin resurfacing treatment that uses gentle abrasion to improve the appearance of uneven skin tone, reducing the appearance of acne scars and fine lines. This treatment also enhances penetration of other skin care products applied to the skin after it.</p>



<p>Microdermabrasion is a non-surgical skin care procedure that stimulates collagen growth and removes the dead skin from your face. It is different to a chemical peel because the latter requires application of a chemical solution to your skin first before using the machine, which removes the dead cells on an even deeper level, Microdermabrasion is a skin resurfacing treatment that uses gentle abrasion to improve the appearance of uneven skin tone, reducing the appearance of acne scars and fine lines.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://cosmeticsenvogue.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/image-1519.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11013" width="413" height="405" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Is Microdermabrasion The Same As A Chemical Peel</h2>



<p>Microdermabrasion is a cosmetic procedure that exfoliates the skin. It uses a tiny vacuum to remove fine layers of dead skin and debris from the outermost layer of your skin, which leaves you with brighter, smoother skin.</p>



<p>Chemical peels are categorized by their depth of penetration into the top layers of your skin. The most superficial peel is an alpha hydroxy acid (AHA) peel, which only penetrates slightly below the surface of your skin. A deeper chemical peel may be called an ultra-hydrating or medium-depth peel. These types of chemical peels can help improve texture, reduce fine lines and wrinkles, and even out pigmentation problems such as melasma.</p>



<p>Microdermabrasion is considered a superficial treatment because it doesn&#8217;t penetrate deeply enough to affect collagen production or resurface damaged tissue beneath the surface of your skin. Chemical peels can help improve fine lines and wrinkles because they can stimulate collagen production in deeper layers of your skin with repeated treatments over time.</p>



<p>Microdermabrasion is a mild exfoliation that uses a vacuum to gently remove dead skin cells and surface debris from the skin. It can be used on all skin types and is an excellent treatment for those with acne, scars, pigmentation, fine lines and wrinkles. Microdermabrasion creates an even surface for new cells to grow in a healthy manner.</p>



<p>Chemical peels are another type of exfoliation, but they work much deeper than microdermabrasion. Chemical peels use a strong acid solution or enzyme gel applied to the face to remove layers of dead skin cells. The procedure takes several minutes and can leave your face red and irritated for several days following treatment. Chemical peels are commonly used to treat fine lines, wrinkles, acne scars and hyperpigmentation (dark patches).</p>



<p>Microdermabrasion is a form of cosmetic skin resurfacing that uses a handheld device to gently remove fine layers of dead skin. This process improves the appearance of scars, wrinkles and blemishes. Microdermabrasion also helps with acne scarring, pigmentation problems and enlarged pores.</p>



<p>Microdermabrasion uses small crystals or salt crystals to “sandblast” your skin, removing the outermost layer of dead skin cells. The crystals are sprayed onto the skin using a vacuum-like wand, which acts like sandpaper on the surface of your face. The crystals are then wiped away with a damp cloth or pad to remove any dead cells from your face, leaving it smoother and younger looking.</p>



<p>Microdermabrasion is not considered surgery because it does not remove tissue or skin grafts like lasers do; instead, this procedure simply removes the outermost layer of skin cells so they can be replaced with new ones through natural cell turnover.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Microdermabrasion vs Chemical Peel split face experiment" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/REHZEY6PG-8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Chemical Peel Vs Microneedling</h2>



<p>Microdermabrasion is a non-surgical skin resurfacing procedure that uses a diamond-tipped wand to gently remove layers of dull, dead skin cells. This leaves your skin with a healthy glow and reduces the appearance of fine lines and wrinkles. Microdermabrasion can be done at home or in a spa or dermatologist&#8217;s office.</p>



<p>Chemical peels are the most common type of facial peel. They remove the outer layer of the skin using a chemical solution that causes the top layer of skin cells to die and flake off over time. Your esthetician can recommend a specific chemical peel based on your skin type, age and desired results.</p>



<p>Both microdermabrasion and chemical peels can improve the appearance of your skin by removing damaged layers and revealing new, healthy skin underneath. However, they are not the same treatment.</p>



<p>Chemical peels are usually done by a dermatologist or plastic surgeon. They can range from very mild to very deep, depending on your skin type and the chemicals used.</p>



<p>The most common chemical peel is called an alpha hydroxy acid (AHA) peel. These peels are designed to remove dead skin cells and make your skin look brighter and smoother. But they don&#8217;t treat acne or wrinkles — those require deeper peels with stronger chemicals.</p>



<p>is microdermabrasion the same as a chemical peel?</p>



<p>Microdermabrasion is a procedure that uses tiny crystals to gently sand away the outer layer of your skin to reveal new, fresh skin underneath. It&#8217;s not meant to be as deep as a chemical peel, but it can help with fine lines and wrinkles, scars, sun damage and even acne scars.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://cosmeticsenvogue.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/image-1520-1024x607.png" alt="" class="wp-image-11016" width="463" height="274" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Microdermabrasion Or Chemical Peel First</h2>



<p>Microdermabrasion is a cosmetic procedure that uses a diamond tip or sandpaper-like wand to gently remove the superficial layer of skin. The treatment can be performed in a doctor&#8217;s office, and it typically takes about half an hour.</p>



<p>Chemical peels are also available at many spas and dermatology offices. They use different chemicals to remove the outermost layers of skin and improve the appearance of your complexion. Chemical peels are usually done under local anesthesia and last longer than microdermabrasion.</p>



<p>Microdermabrasion has some clear advantages over chemical peels: It&#8217;s less expensive, there&#8217;s usually no downtime (or minimal downtime), and you only need one treatment at each visit instead of multiple treatments over time like with chemical peels.</p>



<p>Microdermabrasion is a gentle exfoliation procedure that uses a fine stream of crystals to remove the top layer of skin. It’s often used to treat acne scars, fine lines and wrinkles, hyperpigmentation (dark spots) and enlarged pores.</p>



<p>Chemical peels are another effective method for exfoliating the skin. These treatments use chemicals to remove damaged skin cells, revealing a new layer of fresh skin underneath. Chemical peels can help improve the appearance of acne scars, reduce the appearance of fine lines and wrinkles and brighten your complexion. But they don’t always work as well as microdermabrasion.</p>



<p>Microdermabrasion is a non-surgical skin treatment that uses fine crystals to gently exfoliate the skin. It&#8217;s a great option for those looking to improve their complexion without any invasive procedures.</p>



<p>Chemical peels, on the other hand, are a great way to help achieve younger-looking skin. However, they can be painful and require downtime after the procedure.</p>



<p>Both techniques can be used as part of a full face rejuvenation treatment or as stand-alone procedures. Microdermabrasion is often used in conjunction with chemical peels to smooth out fine lines and wrinkles and prepare your skin for further treatments such as laser hair removal or Botox injections.</p><p>The post <a href="/2023/03/22/is-microdermabrasion-the-same-as-a-chemical-peel/">Is Microdermabrasion The Same As A Chemical Peel</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2023/03/22/is-microdermabrasion-the-same-as-a-chemical-peel/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is Microdermabrasion Or Chemical Peel Better</title>
		<link>/2023/03/22/is-microdermabrasion-or-chemical-peel-better/</link>
					<comments>/2023/03/22/is-microdermabrasion-or-chemical-peel-better/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mhiz Maryam Maryam]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 08:48:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Skin Peel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cosmeticsenvogue.com/?p=10961</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Is Microdermabrasion Or Chemical Peel Better? is often used to improve skin tone, texture and appearance by removing the uppermost layer of old, dead skin cells. It can also treat acne and other skin imperfections such as sun damage as well as age spots, freckles etc, Microdermabrasion or chemical peel? In short: it depends on...</p>
<p>The post <a href="/2023/03/22/is-microdermabrasion-or-chemical-peel-better/">Is Microdermabrasion Or Chemical Peel Better</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Is Microdermabrasion Or Chemical Peel Better? is often used to improve skin tone, texture and appearance by removing the uppermost layer of old, dead skin cells. It can also treat acne and other skin imperfections such as sun damage as well as age spots, freckles etc, Microdermabrasion or chemical peel? In short: it depends on what you&#8217;re wanting to get out of the treatment. If you want an affordable and fast option, microdermabrasion is typically a better choice. But if you want something that lasts longer, you may consider a chemical peel.</p>



<p>Microdermabrasion and chemical peel are two different techniques with the same goal — to make your skin more youthful by improving its texture and appearance. Together they are one of the most popular ways to achieve that healthy, youthful glow, icrodermabrasion or chemical peel better? After all, both seem to provide similar solutions, with their anti-aging benefits. Well, it really depends. Both are highly effective, but have slightly different results.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://cosmeticsenvogue.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/image-1508-1024x877.png" alt="" class="wp-image-10965" width="388" height="332" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Is Microdermabrasion Or Chemical Peel Better</h2>



<p>Microdermabrasion and chemical peels are two very different skin care treatments. Both procedures can be used to remove dead skin cells, but they also have other benefits.</p>



<p>Microdermabrasion uses a hand-piece with tiny crystals that blast away the top layer of dead skin. A chemical peel uses alpha hydroxy acid (AHA) and beta hydroxy acid (BHA) to cause controlled damage to the skin&#8217;s surface. This helps exfoliate the layers of dead skin.</p>



<p>Microdermabrasion can be performed by a medical aesthetician or dermatologist in a medical spa setting or doctor&#8217;s office. Chemical peels are typically performed by medical aestheticians or dermatologists in medical spas, but you can also purchase products at home that contain AHA and BHA ingredients for self-treatment at home.</p>



<p>Benefits of Microdermabrasion</p>



<p>This procedure is great for:</p>



<p>Improving fine lines and wrinkles</p>



<p>Reducing acne scarring and pigmentation issues like melasma (brown spots on the face caused by sun exposure)</p>



<p>Brightening dark spots such as freckles and age spots.</p>



<p>A chemical peel is a treatment that uses chemicals to remove the top layer of skin, revealing younger-looking skin underneath. The procedure can be used to treat fine lines and wrinkles, acne scars, and hyperpigmentation (dark spots).</p>



<p>Chemical peels are performed in the office by a board-certified dermatologist or cosmetic surgeon. They can be done on different areas of the face including around the mouth, eyes, nose, cheeks and forehead.</p>



<p>A microdermabrasion treatment is a form of exfoliation that uses an abrasive device to scrub away dead skin cells on the surface of your face. It’s very similar to an at-home dermabrasion kit but with more precision control over the depth of abrasion. Microdermabrasion treatments are typically done in conjunction with other cosmetic procedures like facelifts or laser treatments.</p>



<p>Microdermabrasion is effective for treating fine lines and wrinkles on the face because it removes dead skin cells from below the surface of your skin without causing damage to live tissue like lasers or chemical peels do.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="CHEMICAL PEEL VS MICRODERMABRASION - Find Out Which One Is Better" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mKExnQp8_fs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Microdermabrasion And Chemical Peel Together</h2>



<p>The microdermabrasion and chemical peel together is a great procedure for anyone that wants to get rid of sun damage, acne scars, age spots, and fine lines. The procedure starts with a microdermabrasion treatment to help exfoliate the surface of your skin. This is followed by a chemical peel to help even out your skin tone and texture.</p>



<p>Both procedures are performed by dermatologists in an office setting using sterile equipment. Both procedures have some downtime associated with them so it&#8217;s important to plan accordingly when scheduling these treatments.</p>



<p>Microdermabrasion</p>



<p>Microdermabrasion is a non-invasive skin resurfacing procedure used to improve the appearance of fine lines and wrinkles on the face and neck. The procedure uses a gentle stream of tiny crystals that dislodge dead skin cells on the outer layer of the epidermis (i.e., the &#8220;skin&#8221; you can see), revealing fresher, healthier looking skin underneath — similar to how sandpaper removes rough surfaces from wood or metal.</p>



<p>Chemical Peel</p>



<p>Chemical peels are used to treat fine lines and wrinkles on the face, as well as acne scarring and hyperpigmentation caused by sun damage or other factors such as hormones or genetics.</p>



<p>Microdermabrasion is a procedure that uses a handpiece to gently remove the outer layer of skin. It can be used on all skin types and is best suited to treat fine lines, superficial wrinkles, uneven pigmentation and acne scars. The treatment is painless, but side effects are possible.</p>



<p>Chemical peels are an exfoliation procedure that uses strong acids or enzymes to remove dead or damaged skin cells. This makes them ideal for treating sun damage, dark spots, fine lines and wrinkles. Chemical peels can be performed on all skin tones and are usually painless; however, side effects are possible with deeper peels.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://cosmeticsenvogue.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/image-1507.png" alt="" class="wp-image-10962" width="409" height="283" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Microdermabrasion Or Chemical Peel For Large Pores</h2>



<p>Microdermabrasion is a process that uses crystals to exfoliate the skin, which can be done at home or in a spa. The crystals are rubbed against the skin, creating friction and heat. This loosens dead skin cells, which then flake off.</p>



<p>The process doesn&#8217;t actually remove any layers of skin, but it can make pores appear smaller by reducing the size of the oil glands inside them.</p>



<p>Chemical peels use acids to exfoliate the skin. Your doctor will apply the acid onto your face with a cotton pad and leave it on for about five minutes before removing it with water or aloe vera gel. This helps remove old layers of skin cells and stimulates new ones to grow in their place.</p>



<p>Microdermabrasion is less invasive than chemical peels because it doesn&#8217;t require anesthesia or downtime (though some people may experience slight redness or irritation after treatment). However, it doesn&#8217;t address deeper issues like sun damage or scarred tissue that may be contributing to large pores on your face. Chemical peels can help treat uneven pigmentation in people with darker complexions and can also help smooth out fine lines and wrinkles around your eyes and mouth.</p>



<p>Microdermabrasion is a safe, non-invasive skin treatment that uses crystals to gently abrade the top layer of dead skin cells. It is a simple process in which an abrasive tip is moved over the skin, loosening and removing dead skin cells.</p>



<p>Chemical peels are another popular option for those who are looking to improve the appearance of their skin. These treatments eliminate damaged and discolored outer layers of skin with chemical solutions that cause mild to moderate irritation on the surface of the skin. Chemical peels can be used on all types of skin, including sensitive and acne-prone.</p>



<p>Both microdermabrasion and chemical peels offer great results for people looking to achieve brighter, smoother and more even-looking complexions. However, if you want to reduce large pores, chemical peels may be your best bet because they can help loosen up sebum plugs (the material clogging up your pores).</p><p>The post <a href="/2023/03/22/is-microdermabrasion-or-chemical-peel-better/">Is Microdermabrasion Or Chemical Peel Better</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2023/03/22/is-microdermabrasion-or-chemical-peel-better/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How To Treat Cold Sore After Chemical Peel</title>
		<link>/2023/03/21/how-to-treat-cold-sore-after-chemical-peel/</link>
					<comments>/2023/03/21/how-to-treat-cold-sore-after-chemical-peel/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Ajay Emancipate]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 13:46:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Skin Peel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cosmeticsenvogue.com/?p=10836</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Cold sores are the worst. They&#8217;re painful, they&#8217;re embarrassing, and they stick around for a long time. If you&#8217;ve ever had one, you know that it&#8217;s not just a little bump on your lip—it&#8217;s a big red sore that lasts for days or weeks at a time. And if you haven&#8217;t had one yet but...</p>
<p>The post <a href="/2023/03/21/how-to-treat-cold-sore-after-chemical-peel/">How To Treat Cold Sore After Chemical Peel</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Cold sores are the worst. They&#8217;re painful, they&#8217;re embarrassing, and they stick around for a long time. If you&#8217;ve ever had one, you know that it&#8217;s not just a little bump on your lip—it&#8217;s a big red sore that lasts for days or weeks at a time. And if you haven&#8217;t had one yet but are planning to get a chemical peel soon, you might be wondering what will happen if your cold sore comes up during the recovery period.</p>



<p>Chemical peels can be a great way to smooth out wrinkles and improve skin tone, but they also have their risks. The most common side effects include dryness, redness, and flaking of the skin—but there are also some more serious side effects that can pop up after a chemical peel. One of these is an outbreak of cold sores (herpes simplex). If you&#8217;ve ever had one of these before and are worried about whether or not it will come back after getting a chemical peel, read on.</p>



<p>Read on to learn more about How To Treat Cold Sore After Chemical Peel</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="https://cosmeticsurgerytips.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/image-1154.png" alt="" class="wp-image-123588" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How To Treat Cold Sore After Chemical Peel</h2>



<p>A chemical peel is a treatment used to improve your skin’s appearance. A chemical solution is applied to the skin, causing the top layers of skin to flake or peel away. This reveals new skin that is smoother, appears less wrinkled and may be more even in color.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">WHAT CAN A CHEMICAL PEEL DO FOR MY SKIN?</h3>



<p>A chemical peel can:</p>



<ul>
<li>Reduce the appearance of fine lines, especially under the eyes and around the mouth.</li>



<li>Treat some skin conditions, such as acne and melasma.</li>



<li>Even out your skin color, especially if you have sun damage, age spots, freckles or blotchiness.</li>



<li>Brighten a dull complexion and smooth rough-feeling skin.</li>
</ul>



<p>Your dermatologist may enhance your results by combining a chemical peel with another procedure, such as a laser treatment or injections with fillers or botulinum toxin. Your dermatologist can determine which treatments will meet your skin care needs.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://cdcssl.ibsrv.net/cimg/www.officiteaadeducationlibrary.smb/343x228_85/985/chemical-peels-1-480985.png" alt="acne" title="" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">HOW IS A CHEMICAL PEEL PERFORMED?</h2>



<p>A chemical peel involves the application of one or more chemical solutions to a certain part of your body, such as the face, neck, chest or hands. The chemical solution usually contains glycolic acid, trichloroacetic acid, salicylic acid, lactic acid or carbolic acid. These acids remove dead skin cells. Many chemical peels use a combination of different acids tailored to treat your specific needs.</p>



<p>Your dermatologist will choose the proper chemical solution and depth of your peel, based on the type of skin damage you have and your desired results.</p>



<p>Once the chemical peel is applied to your skin, your dermatologist will monitor your skin carefully to remove the peel at just the right time.</p>



<p>During a chemical peel, most patients experience a warm to hot sensation that may last about five to 10 minutes. You may experience some stinging. A deeper peel can be more painful and require medication during or after the procedure, and it may have a longer recovery time.</p>



<p>Depending on the depth and strength of the chemical peel, the treatment may be performed in a dermatologist’s office. A deeper peel maybe performed in an outpatient surgical center.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">WHAT ARE THE DIFFERENT TYPES OF CHEMICAL PEELS?</h2>



<ul>
<li>Light or “lunchtime” peel: These mild peels can be performed with little or no downtime. The peels can result in new skin within a week’s time. You may feel a mild sunburn-like sensation on your skin with some redness and scaling. Additional peels can be performed in one- to four-week intervals to achieve more significant improvement.</li>



<li>Medium peel: This is a more intense peel that can result in blistering and swelling of the skin. New skin can appear within two weeks’ time. Follow-up appointments are necessary to ensure proper healing.</li>



<li>Deep peel: This is an intense peel that can require general anesthesia (which means you will be asleep) during the treatment.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">WHAT SHOULD BE EXPECTED AFTER TREATMENT?</h2>



<p>It is important to avoid sun exposure immediately after a chemical peel since the new skin is fragile and more susceptible to injury. Dermatologists recommend that everyone use a broad-spectrum (protects against both UVA and UVB rays), water-resistant sunscreen that has an SPF of 30 or higher.</p>



<p>Your dermatologist may provide you with a moisturizer or a medicated lotion or cream to apply to your skin to help it heal. You also may receive a prescription oral antiviral medication to take for seven to 10 days around the time of your treatment to help prevent cold sores.</p>



<p>Depending on the type of peel, your dermatologist may schedule appropriate follow-up care.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">HOW LONG AFTER A CHEMICAL PEEL CAN I WEAR MAKEUP?</h2>



<p>If you receive a light peel, you can usually wear makeup immediately following the treatment, but sometimes you need to wait until the next day. For a medium peel, you should wait five to seven days before applying makeup. A deep peel requires waiting at least two weeks before wearing makeup.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">WHO SHOULD BE PERFORMING MY CHEMICAL PEEL?</h2>



<p>The results you see after getting a chemical peel depend largely on the skill of the person performing the peel. To protect your health and get the results you seek, you should see a board-certified dermatologist. These doctors have the expertise to evaluate your skin and determine what type of chemical peel would be right for you.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">ARE THERE ANY SIDE EFFECTS FROM A CHEMICAL PEEL?</h2>



<p>Side effects from chemical peels vary depending on the depth of the peel. The deeper the peel, the higher the risk for more severe side effects, such as swelling or prolonged peeling. You may experience persistent redness on your skin that can last several months.</p>



<p>If you have a family history of discoloration of the skin or are taking birth control pills, you may develop a temporary darkening of the skin. Some people who have had medium or deep peels develop permanent changes in their skin color (either lightening or darkening of the skin).</p>



<p>If you are susceptible to cold sores (herpes simplex infections), tell your dermatologist before your chemical peel. You may have a reactivation of cold sores or fever blisters following this treatment.</p>



<p>There is a risk of scarring after a chemical peel, but this risk is very low. If you have a history of keloids, your skin scars easily or you have recurring cold sores, it is important to tell your dermatologist about this before a chemical peel so he or she can take the proper precautions.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">IS A CHEMICAL PEEL APPROPRIATE FOR SKIN OF COLOR?</h2>



<p>It is usually safe for people who have skin of color to have milder chemical peels. Make sure you see a board-certified dermatologist who has expertise using chemical peels to treat darker skin tones. If the person performing the peel does not have this knowledge, people who have skin of color can develop permanent pigment problems.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">HOW EFFECTIVE ARE AT-HOME CHEMICAL PEELS?</h2>



<p>If you are considering using an at-home chemical peel, talk with your dermatologist. At-home chemical peels, even those with low acid concentrations, can cause serious problems if applied incorrectly.</p>



<p>A board-certified dermatologist is a medical doctor who specializes in diagnosing and treating medical, surgical and cosmetic conditions of the skin, hair and nails.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="How to treat cold sores FAST| Dr Dray" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qK8LYS-_qvU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p></p><p>The post <a href="/2023/03/21/how-to-treat-cold-sore-after-chemical-peel/">How To Treat Cold Sore After Chemical Peel</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2023/03/21/how-to-treat-cold-sore-after-chemical-peel/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How To Treat Burns From Chemical Peel</title>
		<link>/2023/03/21/how-to-treat-burns-from-chemical-peel/</link>
					<comments>/2023/03/21/how-to-treat-burns-from-chemical-peel/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Ajay Emancipate]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 10:02:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Skin Peel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cosmeticsenvogue.com/?p=10705</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>A chemical peel treatment is an exfoliation procedure that involves rolling sections of your skin with a chemical solution, like Trichloroacetic acid. They are popular skin treatments because they can improve the texture of your skin and help to reduce acne scars, blemishes and slow down the signs of aging. However, as you know, there...</p>
<p>The post <a href="/2023/03/21/how-to-treat-burns-from-chemical-peel/">How To Treat Burns From Chemical Peel</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A chemical peel treatment is an exfoliation procedure that involves rolling sections of your skin with a chemical solution, like Trichloroacetic acid. They are popular skin treatments because they can improve the texture of your skin and help to reduce acne scars, blemishes and slow down the signs of aging. However, as you know, there are dangerous chemicals involved in the procedure which can cause a number of side effects. One serious risk which you need to be careful about is that it can cause severe burns to your skin that are hard to treat. Follow these steps to treat this type of burns properly before they get any worse and leave permanent damage with scarring.</p>



<p>And while they&#8217;re not as common as other types of injuries, they can be just as serious. After all, burns do more than just hurt—they can cause permanent damage and even death if not treated properly. That&#8217;s why it&#8217;s so important to know how to treat burns when they happen to you or someone else.</p>



<p> Read on to learn more about How To Treat Burns From Chemical Peel, How To Treat Burns After Chemical Peel and How To Treat Burned Skin From Chemical Peel</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://cosmeticsurgerytips.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/image-129.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12519" width="595" height="333" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How To Treat Burns From Chemical Peel</h2>



<p>TCA, or trichloroacetic acid, is an agent used in chemical peels on the face. Demarkation, lesions, and dark spots indicate that the chemical has likely burned the skin or at the very least caused clinically unacceptable outcomes. This could happen if you are experimenting with TCA chemical peels at home.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">HOW DO I TREAT A TCA BURN?</h3>



<p>Please seek an evaluation from your physician or dermatologist.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">HOW DO I PREVENT TCA BURN SCARS?</h3>



<p>There are several modalities to consider when treating dark spots after a TCA burn:</p>



<ul>
<li>Regular use of sunblock.</li>



<li>Hydroquinone, if tolerated.</li>



<li>Retin-A, if possible.</li>



<li>Broadband light or intense pulse light in conjuction with above skincare routine.</li>
</ul>



<p>These are due to postinflammatory hyperpigmentation and this type of pigmentation can be very difficult to completely eradicate; however, with multimodality treatment, we can very successfully improve the appearance of these types of lesions. Treatment includes regular and judicious use of sunblock. Do not confuse sunblock with sunscreens.&nbsp; Sunblock would have titanium dioxide and/or zinc oxide in the ingredients and this would be a sunblock preventing any significant UV from damaging or causing further pigmentation to the skin. This is by far and away the most important step in a treatment regimen for postinflammatory hyperpigmentation.</p>



<p>Other additional treatment options would include hydroquinone applied at least daily if the skin is able to tolerate it. If hydroquinone tends to irritate the skin, this can further produce postinflammatory hyperpigmentation and I would therefore place the patient on Tri-Luma, which has hydroquinone and Retin-A as well as a steroid to reduce the inflammatory reaction.&nbsp;&nbsp;Broadband light&nbsp;or&nbsp;intense pulse light&nbsp;can also be used on postinflammatory hyperpigmentation, but must be used in combination with the aforementioned treatments to prevent further pigmentation from the injury.</p>



<p>Ultimately these areas will greatly improve over time, but there really is no quick fix for postinflammatory hyperpigmentation and most patients will take at least several months to show significant improvement and possibly six months or even longer for resolution of these lesions.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="TCA Peel Burn 35%" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/utFBeagxg5w?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How To Treat Burned Skin From Chemical Peel</h2>



<p>Your Care Instructions</p>



<p>Burns can occur when a harmful chemical, such as a cleaning product or an acid, splashes onto the skin. The amount of damage to the skin depends on how strong the chemical was, how much of it was on the skin, and how long it was there. Chemical burns, even minor ones, can be very painful. A minor burn may heal within a few days. But a more serious burn may take weeks or even months to heal completely.</p>



<p>When the skin is damaged by a burn, it may become infected. You can help prevent infection and help your burn heal. Keep the burn clean, and change the bandages often. Taking good care of the burn as it heals may help prevent bad scars.</p>



<p>The treatment for most chemical burns is to remove the chemical from the skin by flushing the area with plenty of water. But some chemicals can&#8217;t be removed with water. They may need to be removed from the skin in other ways by the doctor.</p>



<p>The doctor has checked your skin carefully, but problems can develop later. If you notice any problems or new symptoms,&nbsp;<strong>get medical treatment right away</strong>.</p>



<p><strong>Follow-up care is a key part of your treatment and safety.</strong>&nbsp;Be sure to make and go to all appointments, and call your doctor or nurse call line if you are having problems. It&#8217;s also a good idea to know your test results and keep a list of the medicines you take.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How To Treat Burns After Chemical Peel</h2>



<p>Chemical peels are a great way to treat acne and wrinkles, but they can also cause damage if you don&#8217;t properly care for your skin after the procedure. If you&#8217;ve recently had a chemical peel or are considering one, here&#8217;s what you need to know about treating burns after chemical peel.</p>



<p>What Are Chemical Peels?</p>



<p>Chemical peels are used to treat a variety of skin conditions, including:</p>



<p>Acne scars</p>



<p>Uneven skin tone</p>



<p>Fine lines and wrinkles</p>



<p>Age spots</p>



<p>Sun damage</p>



<p>How To Treat Burns After Chemical Peel</p>



<p>A chemical peel is a cosmetic procedure that removes the outer layer of skin to improve the texture and appearance of your face. It can also be used to reduce acne scars and smooth out wrinkles.</p>



<p>While chemical peels are usually safe and effective, they do carry some risks. One of these risks is burns, which can occur if the acid used in a chemical peel is too strong or applied too close to your eyes, mouth and nose. If you experience any burning sensations during a chemical peel, contact your doctor right away and follow his instructions for treating burns after chemical peel.</p>



<p>How to Treat Burns After Chemical Peel</p>



<p>To treat burns after chemical peel, follow these steps:</p>



<p>Stop the burn from spreading by immersing affected areas in cool water for at least 15 minutes. Cool compresses will also help relieve burning sensations temporarily until you can get medical attention.</p>



<p>Apply ice packs wrapped in towels to reduce swelling around the burn site; this may help prevent infection if there are open wounds or blisters on your skin. Do not break any blisters yourself — let them heal naturally without touching them with your bare hands as much as possible.</p>



<p>Take pain medication as directed by</p>



<p>If you&#8217;ve ever had a chemical peel, you know how important it is to follow the aftercare instructions. However, it&#8217;s easy to get distracted by the pain or forget what you&#8217;re supposed to do.</p>



<p>Here are the steps for treating burns after a chemical peel:</p>



<p>Clean the area with soap and water. Use cool water for about five minutes. Rinse well. Pat dry with a clean towel.</p>



<p>Apply an antibiotic cream or ointment such as Bacitracin or Neosporin. Apply a thin layer of the cream twice daily for one week or until healed. If your skin feels tight or painful, apply ice to reduce swelling and inflammation.</p>



<p>Chemical peels cause inflammation, which can lead to burns. Burns are red and painful, and they may be covered with blisters. Burns can also lead to scarring.</p>



<p>The best way to treat a chemical peel burn is to use ice or cool water immediately after the treatment. You can also apply aloe vera gel, which has anti-inflammatory properties that may help speed up healing.</p>



<p>If you don’t have any of these products handy, you can make an ice pack by placing a towel in the freezer or using an ice cube wrapped in a paper towel. You can apply this directly to the skin for 20 minutes at a time, several times a day until the burn subsides.</p>



<p>Do not apply any creams or ointments, as these will only trap heat against your skin and make matters worse.</p>



<p>Peeling and flaking are normal after a chemical peel. The skin will heal and return to normal over the next few weeks.</p>



<p>Wash with warm water and mild soap two times per day. Pat dry with a soft towel. Do not rub or scrub your face.</p>



<p>Avoid using any products containing alcohol on your skin until the peeling phase is complete. Alcohol can dry out your skin and make it more susceptible to infection.</p>



<p>Avoid using makeup, moisturizers or sunscreens until your skin has fully healed. These products may irritate your newly exfoliated skin.</p>



<p>﻿</p><p>The post <a href="/2023/03/21/how-to-treat-burns-from-chemical-peel/">How To Treat Burns From Chemical Peel</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2023/03/21/how-to-treat-burns-from-chemical-peel/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is Tattoo Removal Painful</title>
		<link>/2023/03/21/is-tattoo-removal-painful-2/</link>
					<comments>/2023/03/21/is-tattoo-removal-painful-2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mhiz Maryam Maryam]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 09:54:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Skin Peel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cosmeticsenvogue.com/?p=10692</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Is Tattoo Removal Painful process. In fact, many people who get tattoos do so because they want the art on their skin to be permanent. Tattoo removal can be stressful and expensive, but it can also be worthwhile if you&#8217;re looking to remove a tattoo that has become a negative part of your life or...</p>
<p>The post <a href="/2023/03/21/is-tattoo-removal-painful-2/">Is Tattoo Removal Painful</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Is Tattoo Removal Painful process. In fact, many people who get tattoos do so because they want the art on their skin to be permanent. Tattoo removal can be stressful and expensive, but it can also be worthwhile if you&#8217;re looking to remove a tattoo that has become a negative part of your life or no longer fits with your current lifestyle, Tattoo removal is a permanent process that requires several sessions to get rid of your unwanted tattoo. Its a delicate procedure involving the use of laser technology to target the ink that has penetrated the skin.</p>



<p>Tattoos were once just for sailors and prisoners. They became mainstream in the U.S. during the 1970s, however, and although they&#8217;re much more accepted now, people continue to get them. If you have a tattoo and aren&#8217;t happy with it for some reason, you may want to consider having it removed. Perhaps you don&#8217;t like how it looks anymore or maybe the memory it represents has waned to the point where it is no longer meaningful. Here we address what&#8217;s involved in tattoo removal and whether the pain will cause you to regret your decision.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://cosmeticsenvogue.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/image-1444.png" alt="" class="wp-image-10697" width="431" height="308" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Is Tattoo Removal Painful</h2>



<p>Tattoo removal is a long and painful process. The laser can burn the skin, causing scabbing and scarring.</p>



<p>Tattoo removal is a long and painful process. The laser can burn the skin, causing scabbing and scarring. People often don&#8217;t want their tattoos anymore because they&#8217;ve changed their minds about what they want on their body, or because they need to get a job in an industry that doesn&#8217;t allow visible tattoos.</p>



<p>There are many methods of tattoo removal, but not all of them are safe or effective. Here&#8217;s what you need to know about each method:</p>



<p>Laser Tattoo Removal: Laser tattoo removal uses powerful lasers to break up ink particles in the upper layer of your skin without damaging the deeper layers below it. This causes your body to reject the ink particles as it would foreign objects like splinters or dirt particles.</p>



<p>The laser works by targeting individual ink particles within your tattooed area with bursts of intense light energy that breaks them down into smaller pieces — which eventually lead to their complete disappearance from your skin within one or two weeks after treatment!</p>



<p>Tattoo removal is a process of removing a tattoo by destroying the ink in the treated area with a laser. Tattoo removal may be performed on people whose tattoos have adverse implications, such as those who have a tattoo they later regret. Tattoo removal can also be used to treat severe skin damage such as keloids or hypertrophic scars.</p>



<p>Tattoo removal is a surgical procedure that has some risks and side effects, most of them minor but some serious. These include bleeding, infection and scarring.</p>



<p>The pain associated with tattoo removal varies from person to person. Some patients report feeling moderate to intense pain during their treatment sessions, while others experience minimal discomfort.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Is it painful to remove tattoo? - Dr. Rasya Dixit" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HhuRuVgdXDo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Does Tattoo Removal Leave Scars</h2>



<p>Tattoo removal is a safe and effective treatment that offers freedom from unwanted tattoos. Tattoo removal is quite different from laser hair removal, which focuses on a single color. Instead, tattoo removal can remove any color of ink and many different tattoo designs.</p>



<p>Tattoo Removal Safety and Side Effects</p>



<p>Tattoo removal is one of the safest cosmetic procedures available. It&#8217;s true that removing tattoos with lasers can cause some burns, but these burn marks usually fade with time, especially if you protect your skin from the sun.</p>



<p>The main concerns about laser tattoo removal have to do with the risks of ink gathering in your lymph nodes or causing blood clots in your veins (called thrombosis). If you have any questions about these potential side effects, talk to your doctor before undergoing the procedure.</p>



<p>Tattoo removal is a serious business. While tattoos are permanent, there are safe, effective ways to remove them.</p>



<p>There are a number of different methods for removing tattoos, including dermabrasion (sanding down the skin), laser surgery and chemical peels. The most popular form of tattoo removal is with laser surgery, which uses high-power light beams to break up ink pigments with heat and energy.</p>



<p>There are many myths about how safe and effective tattoo removal is. Some people worry about scarring or discoloration after getting their tattoos removed, which can be a problem if the technician does not know what they&#8217;re doing.</p>



<p>In this article I&#8217;ll discuss some of my personal experiences with tattoo removal, as well as provide some tips on how to find an experienced technician who knows what they&#8217;re doing and won&#8217;t leave you scarred or discolored after getting your tattoo removed.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://cosmeticsenvogue.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/image-1446.png" alt="" class="wp-image-10700" width="467" height="293" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Tattoo Removal Before And After</h2>



<p>Tattoo removal is a process that can be done at home or with the help of a professional. The process can be expensive and painful, but it can be worth it if you are looking to remove a tattoo.</p>



<p>What Is Tattoo Removal?</p>



<p>Tattoo removal involves breaking up the pigment particles in your tattoo and removing them from your skin. The ink particles are broken down by using a laser beam that targets the ink in your skin. It&#8217;s an invasive procedure that can take several sessions to complete.</p>



<p>In general, laser tattoo removal works best on smaller tattoos, especially those that have been recently applied. However, it may not work as well on older tattoos or those that have been layered with other types of ink (such as henna).</p>



<p>Tattoo removal is a process that removes tattoos from the skin, usually with laser beams. Tattoo removal is painful and time-consuming, and it can have side effects on the skin.</p>



<p>The most common method of tattoo removal is the surgical method, which involves cutting out the tattooed area of skin and then replacing it with a skin graft. This may cause scarring and other permanent changes in the affected area.</p>



<p>Tattoo removal is a process that removes tattoos from the skin, usually with laser beams. Tattoo removal is painful and time-consuming, and it can have side effects on the skin.</p>



<p>The most common method of tattoo removal is the surgical method, which involves cutting out the tattooed area of skin and then replacing it with a skin graft. This may cause scarring and other permanent changes in the affected area.</p><p>The post <a href="/2023/03/21/is-tattoo-removal-painful-2/">Is Tattoo Removal Painful</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2023/03/21/is-tattoo-removal-painful-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How To Treat Burns After Chemical Peel</title>
		<link>/2023/03/21/how-to-treat-burns-after-chemical-peel/</link>
					<comments>/2023/03/21/how-to-treat-burns-after-chemical-peel/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Ajay Emancipate]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 09:51:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Skin Peel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cosmeticsenvogue.com/?p=10686</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>How to treat burns after a chemical peel. It&#8217;s a fact: Your skin is vulnerable when you&#8217;re getting a chemical peel. But even if your nurse or aesthetician has warned you about the possibility of getting burned, it can still happen. So what do you do if this happens? The first thing to know is...</p>
<p>The post <a href="/2023/03/21/how-to-treat-burns-after-chemical-peel/">How To Treat Burns After Chemical Peel</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>How to treat burns after a chemical peel. It&#8217;s a fact: Your skin is vulnerable when you&#8217;re getting a chemical peel. But even if your nurse or aesthetician has warned you about the possibility of getting burned, it can still happen.</p>



<p>So what do you do if this happens? The first thing to know is that it&#8217;s normal for your skin to feel like it&#8217;s on fire—and it&#8217;s not going to last forever. The second thing is that you need to treat those burns fast.</p>



<p>Read on to learn more aboutbHow To Treat Burns After Chemical Peel, How Can You Care For Yourself At Home? and How To Treat Burned Skin From Chemical Peel</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="https://cosmeticsenvogue.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/image-1445.png" alt="" class="wp-image-10698" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How To Treat Burns After Chemical Peel</h2>



<p></p>



<p>Chemical peels are a great way to treat acne and wrinkles, but they can also cause damage if you don&#8217;t properly care for your skin after the procedure. If you&#8217;ve recently had a chemical peel or are considering one, here&#8217;s what you need to know about treating burns after chemical peel.</p>



<p>What Are Chemical Peels?</p>



<p>Chemical peels are used to treat a variety of skin conditions, including:</p>



<p>Acne scars</p>



<p>Uneven skin tone</p>



<p>Fine lines and wrinkles</p>



<p>Age spots</p>



<p>Sun damage</p>



<p>How To Treat Burns After Chemical Peel</p>



<p>A chemical peel is a cosmetic procedure that removes the outer layer of skin to improve the texture and appearance of your face. It can also be used to reduce acne scars and smooth out wrinkles.</p>



<p>While chemical peels are usually safe and effective, they do carry some risks. One of these risks is burns, which can occur if the acid used in a chemical peel is too strong or applied too close to your eyes, mouth and nose. If you experience any burning sensations during a chemical peel, contact your doctor right away and follow his instructions for treating burns after chemical peel.</p>



<p>How to Treat Burns After Chemical Peel</p>



<p>To treat burns after chemical peel, follow these steps:</p>



<p>Stop the burn from spreading by immersing affected areas in cool water for at least 15 minutes. Cool compresses will also help relieve burning sensations temporarily until you can get medical attention.</p>



<p>Apply ice packs wrapped in towels to reduce swelling around the burn site; this may help prevent infection if there are open wounds or blisters on your skin. Do not break any blisters yourself — let them heal naturally without touching them with your bare hands as much as possible.</p>



<p>Take pain medication as directed by</p>



<p>If you&#8217;ve ever had a chemical peel, you know how important it is to follow the aftercare instructions. However, it&#8217;s easy to get distracted by the pain or forget what you&#8217;re supposed to do.</p>



<p>Here are the steps for treating burns after a chemical peel:</p>



<p>Clean the area with soap and water. Use cool water for about five minutes. Rinse well. Pat dry with a clean towel.</p>



<p>Apply an antibiotic cream or ointment such as Bacitracin or Neosporin. Apply a thin layer of the cream twice daily for one week or until healed. If your skin feels tight or painful, apply ice to reduce swelling and inflammation.</p>



<p>Chemical peels cause inflammation, which can lead to burns. Burns are red and painful, and they may be covered with blisters. Burns can also lead to scarring.</p>



<p>The best way to treat a chemical peel burn is to use ice or cool water immediately after the treatment. You can also apply aloe vera gel, which has anti-inflammatory properties that may help speed up healing.</p>



<p>If you don’t have any of these products handy, you can make an ice pack by placing a towel in the freezer or using an ice cube wrapped in a paper towel. You can apply this directly to the skin for 20 minutes at a time, several times a day until the burn subsides.</p>



<p>Do not apply any creams or ointments, as these will only trap heat against your skin and make matters worse.</p>



<p>Peeling and flaking are normal after a chemical peel. The skin will heal and return to normal over the next few weeks.</p>



<p>Wash with warm water and mild soap two times per day. Pat dry with a soft towel. Do not rub or scrub your face.</p>



<p>Avoid using any products containing alcohol on your skin until the peeling phase is complete. Alcohol can dry out your skin and make it more susceptible to infection.</p>



<p>Avoid using makeup, moisturizers or sunscreens until your skin has fully healed. These products may irritate your newly exfoliated skin.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-4-3 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Chemical peel gone wrong! | Lois A." width="640" height="480" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NSJ7FyOO9Ws?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How To Treat Burned Skin From Chemical Peel</h2>



<p>Your Care Instructions</p>



<p>Burns can occur when a harmful chemical, such as a cleaning product or an acid, splashes onto the skin. The amount of damage to the skin depends on how strong the chemical was, how much of it was on the skin, and how long it was there. Chemical burns, even minor ones, can be very painful. A minor burn may heal within a few days. But a more serious burn may take weeks or even months to heal completely.</p>



<p>When the skin is damaged by a burn, it may become infected. You can help prevent infection and help your burn heal. Keep the burn clean, and change the bandages often. Taking good care of the burn as it heals may help prevent bad scars.</p>



<p>The treatment for most chemical burns is to remove the chemical from the skin by flushing the area with plenty of water. But some chemicals can&#8217;t be removed with water. They may need to be removed from the skin in other ways by the doctor.</p>



<p>The doctor has checked your skin carefully, but problems can develop later. If you notice any problems or new symptoms,&nbsp;<strong>get medical treatment right away</strong>.</p>



<p><strong>Follow-up care is a key part of your treatment and safety.</strong>&nbsp;Be sure to make and go to all appointments, and call your doctor or nurse call line if you are having problems. It&#8217;s also a good idea to know your test results and keep a list of the medicines you take.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://cosmeticsurgerytips.com/91c4de70-b2fb-49cd-b403-31151204ecf8" alt="" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How Can You Care For Yourself At Home?</h2>



<ul>
<li>If your doctor told you how to care for your burn, follow your doctor&#8217;s instructions. If you did not get instructions, follow this general advice:
<ul>
<li>Wash the burn with clean water 2 times a day. Don&#8217;t use hydrogen peroxide or alcohol, which can slow healing.</li>



<li>Gently pat the burn dry after you wash it.</li>



<li>You may cover the burn with a thin layer of petroleum jelly, such as Vaseline, and a non-stick bandage.</li>



<li>Apply more petroleum jelly and replace the bandage as needed.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Be safe with medicines. Read and follow all instructions on the label.
<ul>
<li>If the doctor gave you a prescription medicine for pain, take it as prescribed.</li>



<li>If you are not taking a prescription pain medicine, ask your doctor if you can take an over-the-counter medicine.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Don&#8217;t break blisters open. Broken blisters could get infected. If a blister breaks open by itself, blot up the liquid, and leave the skin that covered the blister. This helps protect the new skin.</li>



<li>Try not to scratch the burn. Talk to your doctor or nurse call line about what to use on the burn for </li>
</ul>



<p></p>



<p>.</p>



<p>﻿</p><p>The post <a href="/2023/03/21/how-to-treat-burns-after-chemical-peel/">How To Treat Burns After Chemical Peel</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2023/03/21/how-to-treat-burns-after-chemical-peel/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!--
Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: https://www.boldgrid.com/w3-total-cache/

Object Caching 89/115 objects using apc
Page Caching using apc (Requested URI contains query) 
Database Caching 16/23 queries in 0.116 seconds using apc

Served from: cosmeticsenvogue.eclipse1803.com @ 2023-04-07 14:11:27 by W3 Total Cache
-->