<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Tummy Tuck - Blog</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/tummy-tuck/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>My WordPress Blog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 13:28:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Can I Push To Poop After Tummy Tuck</title>
		<link>/2023/03/22/can-i-push-to-poop-after-tummy-tuck/</link>
					<comments>/2023/03/22/can-i-push-to-poop-after-tummy-tuck/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Ajay Emancipate]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 13:28:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tummy Tuck]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cosmeticsenvogue.com/?p=11231</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>When is it safe to push to poop after tummy tuck? The answer: it depends. There are many factors that can influence when and whether you can push to poop after a tummy tuck, but the most important thing to remember is that your doctor is always the best source of information about your recovery....</p>
<p>The post <a href="/2023/03/22/can-i-push-to-poop-after-tummy-tuck/">Can I Push To Poop After Tummy Tuck</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When is it safe to push to poop after tummy tuck? The answer: it depends. There are many factors that can influence when and whether you can push to poop after a tummy tuck, but the most important thing to remember is that your doctor is always the best source of information about your recovery. He or she will be able to give you guidance on what you should expect during the first few days after your operation and will be able to tell you if there are any concerns that may arise during this time.</p>



<p>In general, however, here are some things to keep in mind: Your doctor may recommend that you avoid eating solid foods until the day after your procedure, so as not to risk aggravating any potential incisions, which could cause infection.</p>



<p> Read on to learn more about Can I Push To Poop After Tummy Tuck</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://cosmeticsurgerytips.com/872b7760-a8f7-4ad0-a06b-7e5c61371abf" alt="" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Can I Push To Poop After Tummy Tuck</h2>



<p>I would recommend you to wait until you see your doctor. The general rule is that you must wait for 2 weeks after a tummy tuck. I have seen patients who could not move their bowels for 4 weeks after the surgery, but again this is rare.</p>



<p>In short, push as hard as you can and if nothing comes out then its nothing to worry about.</p>



<p>Yes, you can push to poop after a tummy tuck. I would wait at least a week or two after your surgery to try this.</p>



<p>You will probably be constipated for the first few days after your operation. This is because you are not eating much, and the bowel is less active with less food going through it. You may also have pain medication that slows down bowel function.</p>



<p>After about 3 days to a week, most people get back to normal bowel function. If you are still having trouble pooping after this time frame, then talk to your surgeon or nurse. They might give you a laxative or stool softener if they think that is what is needed</p>



<p>You can push to poop after Tummy Tuck.</p>



<p>The most important thing is to make sure that you are not straining yourself. You should be able to have a bowel movement without discomfort and without pushing. If you have a lot of pain or difficulty, please see your doctor.</p>



<p>If you&#8217;ve had a Tummy Tuck, it&#8217;s important to remember that your abdominal muscles were cut and stitched back together. It may take some time for these muscles to heal completely. In fact, it can take up to 4-6 weeks for them to heal completely. So, don&#8217;t be surprised if your bowels don&#8217;t function normally right away after surgery. This can cause constipation or hard stools (because the intestines cannot work properly). A lot depends on how long you were constipated before surgery and how much stool was in your intestines (before surgery).</p>



<p>If you haven&#8217;t been constipated for a long time (or ever), then this may not be a problem for you at all! But if it does become an issue, then here are some tips:</p>



<p>1) Drink lots of water &#8211; this helps soften the stool;</p>



<p>2) Eat more fiber &#8211; this also helps soften the stool;</p>



<p>3) Try</p>



<p>If you have had a tummy tuck, it is very important that you do not strain to poop. If you have any bleeding or pain, call your doctor immediately.</p>



<p>Some patients are constipated after surgery and may need to take laxatives or stool softeners to help the bowels move.</p>



<p>You should be able to push out a bowel movement by three weeks post operatively (or earlier if it is soft). If you are having difficulty with bowel movements, please let your surgeon know so they can help determine if this is normal or an issue that needs attention.</p>



<p>Hi there,</p>



<p>It is not uncommon to feel the need to push after an operation like a tummy tuck. It is important that you do not push at all during this time and wait until you are in less pain before attempting to go. The best thing you can do is take stool softeners such as Colace or Senakot to help with the passage of stool. You should also avoid constipation by eating lots of fiber rich foods like fruits and vegetables and drinking plenty of water.</p>



<p>The area where your surgery was performed will remain swollen for several months after surgery and it will be important to avoid straining when going to the bathroom as well as taking care not to get constipated.</p>



<p>I hope this helps!</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="How do I attend the toilet after a tummy tuck?" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FQKjGv7MeDY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Weight loss after mini tummy tuck</h2>



<p>Weight loss after mini tummy tuck</p>



<p>The issue of weight loss after a mini tummy tuck is controversial.</p>



<p>A mini tummy tuck is a procedure that removes fat, skin, and/or muscle in order to tighten the abdominal area. The procedure leaves the patient with a long scar running across the lower abdomen, but this scar is hidden under clothing and only visible when the patient wears bikinis or dresses.</p>



<p>There are several types of mini tummy tucks, including transabdominal mini tummy tucks, which means they are performed through an incision in the abdominal wall. A transabdominal mini tummy tuck can be combined with other procedures such as liposuction to remove excess fat from other areas of the body.</p>



<p>This type of surgery is appropriate for people who have just a small amount of excess skin that needs tightening. It&#8217;s also beneficial for people who are not overweight but want an improvement in their overall appearance.</p>



<p>The weight loss after a mini tummy tuck is usually around 10%. Unfortunately, there is no way to predict how much weight you will lose after surgery.</p>



<p>You should discuss your weight loss goals with your surgeon before your procedure. This way, they can plan the best course of action for achieving the results you want.</p>



<p>You should also follow a healthy diet and exercise program to help you reach your goals.</p>



<p>It is important to note that any type of surgery carries risks, including death and complications. Your doctor will explain these risks to you beforehand so that you know what to expect from this procedure.</p>



<p>Weight loss after mini tummy tuck</p>



<p>The best way to know if you are a candidate is to get a consultation with your surgeon.</p>



<p>Most patients who have experienced weight loss do well after surgery, but it is important that you are realistic about what your body can achieve. If you are very overweight and have been trying unsuccessfully to lose weight before surgery, it may be best to wait until you have lost some weight before having the procedure done.</p>



<p>By waiting until you are in better shape, it will give both your skin and abdominal muscles more elasticity and strength so they can withstand the stresses of surgery. It is also important that you do not smoke or drink alcohol excessively prior to or after surgery as this can increase your risk of complications such as infection or bleeding during or after surgery.</p>



<p>Weight loss after a mini tummy tuck is a common problem. Many patients are disappointed when they lose only a few pounds after the surgery.</p>



<p>The reason for this is that the stomach is not the only place where fats are stored in the body. The hips, thighs, buttocks and upper arms also store fat. If you lose weight from these areas, it will not be noticeable on your stomach.</p>



<p>The best way to determine if you can expect to lose weight after mini tummy tuck is to meet with a board-certified plastic surgeon who can examine you and discuss your expectations realistically.</p>



<p>If you have realistic expectations and choose the right surgeon, you should be pleased with the results of your surgery.</p>



<p>The best way to lose weight after a mini tummy tuck is to follow the same guidelines you would use for any other weight loss.</p>



<p>First and foremost, you need to eat healthy foods. This means avoiding processed foods, refined sugars and carbohydrates. Instead, focus on eating whole foods such as fruits, vegetables and lean proteins.</p>



<p>You should also make sure that you are getting enough sleep each night as well as staying active during the day. This will help keep your metabolism up so you can burn calories more efficiently throughout the day.</p>



<p>If possible, it is also a good idea to get some exercise into your routine at least three times per week. This could be something like walking or jogging but it can also include strength training exercises if you prefer this type of activity over cardio workouts.</p>



<p>While there are no specific rules about how long it takes to lose weight after having a mini tummy tuck surgery performed on you, most people will see their results start to show within about six months after their procedure was performed on them.</p><p>The post <a href="/2023/03/22/can-i-push-to-poop-after-tummy-tuck/">Can I Push To Poop After Tummy Tuck</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2023/03/22/can-i-push-to-poop-after-tummy-tuck/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Do You Know If You Need A Tummy Tuck</title>
		<link>/2023/03/22/how-do-you-know-if-you-need-a-tummy-tuck-2/</link>
					<comments>/2023/03/22/how-do-you-know-if-you-need-a-tummy-tuck-2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Ajay Emancipate]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 12:43:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tummy Tuck]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cosmeticsenvogue.com/?p=11192</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Tummy tuck surgery is a procedure that removes excess skin and fat from the abdominal area and tightens the muscles of the abdomen. The doctor will make an incision near the belly button and remove excess skin, fat and tissue from the lower abdomen. The surgeon will then tighten the muscles in this area with...</p>
<p>The post <a href="/2023/03/22/how-do-you-know-if-you-need-a-tummy-tuck-2/">How Do You Know If You Need A Tummy Tuck</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tummy tuck surgery is a procedure that removes excess skin and fat from the abdominal area and tightens the muscles of the abdomen. The doctor will make an incision near the belly button and remove excess skin, fat and tissue from the lower abdomen. The surgeon will then tighten the muscles in this area with sutures or stitches, which helps to give you a firmer tummy.</p>



<p>Your doctor may also perform liposuction on your lower back, hips and thighs to help improve your overall body contour. The tummy tuck procedure is often combined with other procedures to provide you with an overall better contour such as a breast lift or eyelid surgery.</p>



<p>Read on to learn more about How Do You Know If You Need A Tummy Tuck, Tummy Tuck Risks Of Death and Tummy Tuck Complications Years Later</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="https://cosmeticsurgerytips.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-546.png" alt="" class="wp-image-108427" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How Do You Know If You Need A Tummy Tuck</h2>



<p>Are you ready to have your pre-baby body back but discouraged that your diet and exercise efforts haven’t been effective? Or, have you lost a significant amount of weight only to find you have excess, loose skin that hasn’t “tightened up” with time? In either situation, it’s common to have skin that has been pushed past its elasticity limit and can no longer bounce back.</p>



<p>While liposuction can remove excess fat around the waistline and lower abdomen, it cannot remedy excess skin or weak muscles that allow your abdomen to bulge. At Southern Surgical Arts, we frequently combine liposculpture with a tummy tuck procedure, so that we can address lax skin and weak muscles with surgery, as well as create more beautiful contours via liposuction. The result is a beautiful, post-pregnancy or weight loss body that anybody would be proud to show off.</p>



<p>Keep reading to learn five signs that a tummy tuck might be appropriate for you.</p>



<p>Loose abdominal muscles. If your abdominal muscles seem resistant to exercise and are no longer providing the support you need, a tummy tuck surgery can address this problem. A skilled cosmetic surgeon can separate the layers of skin and fat from the muscle and then pull the muscles together at the midline, creating tighter, firmer muscles and a flatter stomach.</p>



<p><br>Extreme skin laxity and excess fat. If your skin has little to no elasticity left, you will likely need a tummy tuck to improve its appearance. Once skin has become lax and “stretched out,” even removing any fat behind it will not fix the situation. Skin laxity is not only caused by the stretching that occurs during pregnancy, it also can occur in people who have lost significant weight via dieting or gastric bypass. Tummy tucks are not just for mommies, but for anyone who has excess skin and fat—including men.</p>



<p><br>Still wearing maternity clothes months (or years) after giving birth. Celebrities’ careers depend on getting their pre-baby bellies back in record time, but that’s just not realistic for most of us. However, if after a year of dieting and exercise you haven’t seen any improvement and find wearing non-maternity clothes uncomfortable, you might wish to discuss a tummy tuck with a skilled cosmetic surgeon. Additionally, if you have slimmed down considerably after dieting or bypass surgery, you may be frustrated that you have lost so many pounds only to find your clothing options are still limited. A tummy tuck can make a huge difference in how you look in your clothes (as well as out of them!)</p>



<p><br>Significant stretch marks. Unfortunately, there is still no perfect solution for stretch marks. We can fade the color of new stretch marks significantly—and sometimes improve the texture of old ones—with devices like the Dermapen, but there is currently no treatment that can permanently erase them. However, if you have excess skin removed during a tummy tuck, most stretch marks will be removed as well. If there are any remaining stretch marks, they will likely be much lower on your abdomen where they are less visible. And, your beautiful new curves and sculpted muscles will draw attention away from them!</p>



<p><br>Decreased body confidence. One of the best reasons to have a tummy tuck may simply be that you do not feel confident about yourself and body. Decreased self-confidence can negatively impact your personal life, your sex life, and how you interact with others at work and play. It’s important to look and feel your best, and it may be hard to do that if you are feeling self-conscious and less than secure in your appearance.<br>You might be a candidate for a tummy tuck if you are:</p>



<p>Age 25 to 65<br>Non-smoker<br>Generally in good health<br>Desire a flatter stomach, stronger abdominal muscles and a more beautiful, sculpted waistline<br>The surgery is available for both men and women.</p>



<p>A tummy tuck can greatly boost your body-confidence and comfort, especially when performed by a qualified cosmetic surgeon with the ability to balance technique and artistry to achieve the most beautiful results. Dr. Carey Nease and Dr. Chad Deal are award-winning, board-certified cosmetic surgeons who have performed more than 700 tummy tuck procedures.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="5 Things About Tummy Tucks You Should Know" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/w2GQuWBOH_c?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Tummy Tuck Risks Of Death</h2>



<p id="block-f05d2db9-d3b1-4133-8691-49dd7b857d2f">Abdominoplasty&nbsp;alone is considered a &#8220;major&#8221; surgical procedure in terms of risk and impact on normal homeostasis. Relative to other aesthetic surgical procedures, it is associated with higher rates of morbidity and morality, although with lower rates when compared with such reconstructive procedures as craniofacial surgery. According to Grazer and Goldwyn, it carries a mortality rate of 1:617 (.16 percent). about the same as that of hang gliding (1:600). A recent survey reported a rate as 1:2324 (.04 percent). The implication is that abdominoplasty has a significant and definable mortality risk associated with it; therefore, any additional procedure added to an abdominoplasty with further risk should caution the surgeon to minimize adverse outcomes before proceeding. Since not operating incurs no medical hardships, any further risks imposed by liposuction must be weighed by the physician and patient against potential gains.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="block-155a9ffa-333a-4a82-b1d8-4950ff20e60a">Department of Plastic Surgery, Queen Mary&#8217;s Hospital, London</h4>



<p id="block-08a57087-1f8d-4757-91e3-bdb1e0a4ddd8">A 6-year retrospective series of 133 abdominoplasties was studied and type and incidence of complications are presented. From this series a group of 34 patients was re-examined between 4 and 10 1/2 years postoperatively and conclusions were made from this long-term follow-up. A high incidence of injury to the lateral cutaneous nerve of the thigh was recorded. A blood transfusion was required in 19% of the cases, the average hospitalization was 12.4 days and the complication rate ranged between 24% in those who did not attend review and 65% in those who were re-examined. Objectively judged, 55% of the patients had excellent or good results, but subjective patient satisfaction was nearly 90%.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="block-30becc66-282d-4183-be5c-b1f1781c1703">A Safer Alternative</h3>



<p id="block-fb7806b0-a3bd-40f9-8f88-7d39713b51f9">We recommend instead the&nbsp;Yoho Method&nbsp;<strong>&#8220;No Scalpel Tummy Tuck&#8221;</strong>, done with liposuction, which in most cases gives you a much better result with skin shrinkage and almost no scarring. If you are indeed a tummy tuck candidate, we will tell you. For more information, read &#8220;Liposuction vs. Tummy Tucks&#8221;.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="https://cosmeticsurgerytips.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-547.png" alt="" class="wp-image-108429" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="block-0aba502c-9453-4d76-85e0-5f5ae1f6ca17">Tummy Tuck Complications Years Later</h2>



<p id="block-0d9ddc04-9d04-44e0-83e0-400a4ae2bde6">Abdominoplasty—sometimes called &#8220;tummy tuck&#8221;—has a higher risk of major complications than other cosmetic plastic surgery procedures, reports a study in the November issue of&nbsp;<em>Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery</em>®, the official medical journal of the American Society of Plastic Surgeons (ASPS).</p>



<p id="block-ac5a3e09-4550-493a-a58c-6b7d3393e847">Complication risk is particularly high for the large proportion of patients undergoing abdominoplasty in combination with other procedures, according to an analysis of nationwide data by Dr. Julian Winocour of Vanderbilt University, Nashville, and colleagues. They write, &#8220;Combined procedures can significantly increase complication rates and should be considered carefully in higher-risk patients.&#8221;</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="block-f79278aa-60b9-47fe-9957-024aa788a893">Database Shows High Risk of Major Complications after Abdominoplasty</h4>



<p id="block-1417a5cd-4a4c-40e1-8630-4ab791ee1b06">The researchers assessed abdominoplasty complication rates and risk factors using the nationwide CosmetAssure database. CosmetAssure is an insurance program providing coverage for complications related to cosmetic plastic surgery procedures, which are typically not covered by health insurance.</p>



<p id="block-4fb2b182-d2a2-4b1d-90c8-a823767f2f2a">The study included nearly 25,000 abdominoplasties performed between 2008 and 2013, representing about 14 percent of all procedures in the database. Abdominoplasty is done to remove excess skin and tissue from the abdomen, to create a smoother, firmer abdominal profile.</p>



<p id="block-79a3ab78-f101-4646-a101-6614433b739b">Ninety-seven percent of abdominoplasty patients were women; the average age was 42 years. Sixty-five percent of patients underwent abdominoplasty combined with other cosmetic surgery procedures.</p>



<p id="block-aab2a11b-3114-4fc1-8695-3c7102770551">Overall, major complications occurred in four percent of patients undergoing abdominoplasty—significantly higher than the 1.4 percent rate after other cosmetic surgery procedures. (The database didn&#8217;t include less-serious complications that can be managed in the clinic). Hematomas (blood collections) were the most common major complication, followed by infections, blood clots (venous thromboembolism), and lung-related problems.</p>



<p id="block-59980a44-078f-4aac-99d3-8887d5781856">Combined procedures were a key risk factor for complications. Compared to the 3.1 percent rate with abdominoplasty alone, risk increased when abdominoplasty was combined with other procedures: up to 10.4 percent when abdominoplasty was combined with body contouring plus liposuction. After adjustment for other factors, the relative risk of major complications was 50 percent higher with combined procedures.</p>



<p id="block-87c44e70-2b9a-4716-b913-1f25d3fa9446">Other risk factors for major complications included male sex, age 55 years or older, and obesity. Risk was lower when abdominoplasty was performed in an office-based surgical suite, compared to a hospital or surgical center. Dr. Winocour comments, &#8220;Surgeons often refer patients with major illnesses, such as heart disease, to hospitals, which may be responsible for this observed trend in complications.&#8221;</p>



<p id="block-a97cf977-acac-4a63-a4da-1a593fa42ac6">Diabetes and smoking—two major surgical risk factors—were not associated with a significant increase in complications after abdominoplasty. &#8220;That likely reflected Board-certified plastic surgeons&#8217; practice of not offering abdominoplasty to poorly controlled diabetics and recommending strict smoking cessation for at least four weeks before and after surgery,&#8221; Dr. Wincour adds.</p>



<p id="block-bca5392d-869e-42a5-92e0-ff06ec2fec76">Abdominoplasty is the sixth most common cosmetic surgical procedure performed in the United States, with more than 117,000 procedures performed in 2014, according to ASPS statistics. The number of abdominoplasties has increased in recent years—partly because of the increased number of patients undergoing body contouring surgery to remove excess skin and tissue after massive weight loss.</p>



<p id="block-b75ff350-29df-475a-ac68-4ccbb53d04fd">The study adds to previous evidence that abdominoplasty carries a higher complication rate than other cosmetic plastic surgery procedures. &#8220;Although the overall incidence of major complications is low, such complications can leave a potentially devastating cosmetic outcome and pose a significant financial burden on the patient and surgeon,&#8221; the researchers write.</p>



<p id="block-ce1d70f1-11f5-4619-a90b-632c02c321f7">They draw special attention to the risk associated with multiple procedures—especially since nearly two-thirds of patients in the database underwent other cosmetic procedures combined with abdominoplasty. Dr. Winocour and colleagues suggest that some patients at high risk of complications might be better off undergoing staged rather than combination procedures.</p>



<p id="block-51145011-32f2-4975-9b98-4b7dc2ee7dcb"><em>Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery</em>® is published by Wolters Kluwer.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="block-c2c9f273-d341-4a04-ac4e-b07d8ff9635b">About Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery</h4>



<p id="block-b0a1f7e7-ee45-47bc-baa7-770db3b14a0b">For over 75 years,&nbsp;<em>Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery</em>® has been the one consistently excellent reference for every specialist who uses plastic surgery techniques or works in conjunction with a plastic surgeon. The official journal of the American Society of Plastic Surgeons,&nbsp;<em>Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery</em>® brings subscribers up-to-the-minute reports on the latest techniques and follow-up for all areas of plastic and reconstructive surgery, including breast reconstruction, experimental studies, maxillofacial reconstruction, hand and microsurgery, burn repair and cosmetic surgery, as well as news on medico-legal issues.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="block-384cf591-3b48-413c-b0db-3e1956232f69">About ASPS</h4>



<p id="block-c4350bf2-efcc-497a-8632-d52b77cd6c1c">The&nbsp;American Society of Plastic Surgeons&nbsp;(ASPS) is the largest organization of board-certified plastic surgeons in the world. Representing more than 7,000 physician members, the society is recognized as a leading authority and information source on cosmetic and reconstructive plastic surgery. ASPS comprises more than 93 percent of all board-certified plastic surgeons in the United States. Founded in 1931, the society represents physicians certified by The American Board of Plastic Surgery or The Royal College of Physicians and Surgeons of Canada.</p><p>The post <a href="/2023/03/22/how-do-you-know-if-you-need-a-tummy-tuck-2/">How Do You Know If You Need A Tummy Tuck</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2023/03/22/how-do-you-know-if-you-need-a-tummy-tuck-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Long Does Swelling Last After Tummy Tuck</title>
		<link>/2023/03/22/how-long-does-swelling-last-after-tummy-tuck-2/</link>
					<comments>/2023/03/22/how-long-does-swelling-last-after-tummy-tuck-2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Ajay Emancipate]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 12:43:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tummy Tuck]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cosmeticsenvogue.com/?p=11191</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Suppose you are going out with a close friend and get dressed up, high heels, and all. You look in the mirror and head out to meet your friend. But when you reach the door you realize that something is wrong — very wrong indeed. Your pants are too tight. You&#8217;re sure that you didn&#8217;t...</p>
<p>The post <a href="/2023/03/22/how-long-does-swelling-last-after-tummy-tuck-2/">How Long Does Swelling Last After Tummy Tuck</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Suppose you are going out with a close friend and get dressed up, high heels, and all. You look in the mirror and head out to meet your friend. But when you reach the door you realize that something is wrong — very wrong indeed. Your pants are too tight. You&#8217;re sure that you didn&#8217;t put on any weight recently. Plus, your favorite shirt is now hanging off one shoulder at a strange angle, like a wet noodle being pulled by the left side of your body.</p>



<p>Swelling is usually the first of the postoperative symptoms to occur after a tummy tuck surgery. It&#8217;s also one of the longest lasting symptoms too, usually lasting up to 6 months or longer in some cases. It&#8217;s important though that you know that your doctor will never approve of you having this procedure if they feel your body type will not tolerate the outcome thereafter. Let me tell you more about this from personal experience and how a tummy tuck can help alleviate swelling and make you feel more confident about your appearance.</p>



<p>Read on to learn more on How Long Does Swelling Last After Tummy Tuck , How Long Before I Can Stand Straight After Tummy Tuck and Warning Signs After Tummy Tuck</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://cosmeticsurgerytips.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-725-1024x576.png" alt="" class="wp-image-109052" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How Long Does Swelling Last After Tummy Tuck</h2>



<p> </p>



<p>It&#8217;s difficult to know exactly how long swelling will last after a tummy tuck, as this varies from patient to patient. Swelling may last from one to three months, although it is common for patients to still have some swelling at six months after the procedure.</p>



<p>Swelling can affect different parts of your body and occur in varying degrees. Some areas may be more susceptible than others, such as the neck or eyelids. Swelling in these areas can cause discoloration and fluid retention. The affected skin may also become hard or tight and may develop blisters or small bumps called granulomas.</p>



<p>If you experience any of these symptoms, contact your doctor immediately. They may prescribe medications that reduce swelling quickly and help prevent complications, such as blood clots or infections. In severe cases, surgery may be necessary to remove excess fluid around the body caused by swelling</p>



<p>Most patients experience swelling for 2-3 weeks after surgery. This is normal, and usually goes away on its own.</p>



<p>If you experience severe swelling or pain, contact your surgeon. It is important to let them know if you are having any problems or concerns post-operatively so they can address them immediately.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">What can you not do after a tummy tuck?</h4>



<p>As a tummy tuck involves making an incision from one hip to the other, you must avoid certain movements and activities to reduce the risk of damaging your stitches.For the first few days following surgery, you will not be able to stand fully straight as this will pull on your stitches, so you will need to keep a slight bend at the hips.</p>



<p>Lying flat with your legs extended out in front is to be avoided in the first few weeks to prevent tearing your stitches, so it is recommended to either sleep in a recliner chair or to place pillows under your knees to keep them bent.</p>



<p>You will need to take time off work for the first two to four weeks following surgery so you can rest and recover; you will also not be able to undertake any strenuous exercise, raise your arms, or lift weights for at least six to twelve weeks.</p>



<p>While taking pain medication, it is also recommended you avoid alcohol.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">How long does the pain last after a tummy tuck?</h4>



<p>You will feel sore for the first few days following surgery, so you will be prescribed pain medication to help you feel more comfortable. However, the discomfort should begin to subside within the first couple of weeks.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">How long does it take to fully recover from a tummy tuck?</h4>



<p>The type of tummy tuck you have had and how quickly your body heals will impact how long tummy tuck recovery lasts. However, most people will be fully recovered within four to eight weeks.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">How long after a tummy tuck can I drive?</h4>



<p>Simple movements such as twisting to check your blind spot, turning the steering wheel, or opening and closing a car door can all compromise your wound healing and cause discomfort, which is why it is recommended you avoid driving for the first few weeks after surgery.</p>



<p>Your healthcare team will advise you when it is safe for you to resume driving, however, most people are usually able to start driving again within two to four weeks.</p>



<p></p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
https://cosmeticsurgerytips.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-725-1024&#215;576.png
</div></figure>



<p></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How Long Before I Can Stand Straight After Tummy Tuck</h2>



<p>I am a little over 4 weeks post op and my surgeon has me standing up straight. I am still having some pain around my incision area. He told me to take it easy and continue my exercises.</p>



<p>I was wondering how long before i can stand straight after tummy tuck?</p>



<p>The tummy tuck usually takes about two hours to complete. You should be able to stand straight after the surgery, but you will need to use a walker for about two weeks. After that, you should be able to get up and walk around without any help. The pain should subside within a few days of your surgery.</p>



<p>You might experience some swelling and bruising after your procedure, so make sure you wear loose-fitting clothing and take it easy during the first few days after your tummy tuck. If you have any questions or concerns, talk with your doctor as soon as possible.</p>



<p>If you have a tummy tuck, you may be surprised by how quickly you can get back to your normal activities. After surgery, you&#8217;ll need to lie on your back for several days and then switch to your side. You&#8217;ll also need help getting up and walking around for the first few days after your surgery.</p>



<p>After about two weeks, you should be able to get up and walk around unassisted, but it can take up to six weeks before you&#8217;re fully healed. Your doctor will give specific instructions about when it&#8217;s safe for you to start exercising again.</p>



<p>If you have other surgical procedures at the same time as a tummy tuck, such as liposuction or breast augmentation, these factors could delay healing and recovery time.</p>



<p>It is important to follow your surgeon&#8217;s instructions for recovery. Most surgeons advise that you not stand straight for at least 6 weeks after surgery. After 6 weeks, it will still be some time before you can return to normal activities without pain and discomfort.</p>



<p>In general, the recovery process takes anywhere from 6 weeks to 6 months depending on the individual patient, the extent of the surgery, and how well they follow their surgeon&#8217;s instructions.</p>



<p>For example: a tummy tuck with liposuction may take longer than a tummy tuck without liposuction because there is more tissue damage during liposuction and more swelling after liposuction than there is after an uncomplicated tummy tuck without liposuction.</p>



<p>The tummy tuck procedure is a major operation and you should be prepared for some pain. You will have a drain placed in your abdomen after surgery to help remove any fluid or blood that may accumulate. The drain may stay in for up to 10 days.</p>



<p>You will also have a compression garment to wear for 3-4 weeks after surgery. It will help reduce swelling and tightness of the skin. Strenuous activity should be avoided for several weeks after surgery, but most patients are able to return to work within 1-2 weeks of surgery.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://cosmeticsurgerytips.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-725-1024x576.png" alt="" class="wp-image-109052" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Warning Signs After Tummy Tuck</h2>



<p>The tummy tuck is one of the most popular cosmetic surgeries. The procedure involves removing excess skin, fat and muscles from the lower abdomen and tightening the abdominal wall.</p>



<p>The surgery can be performed using different approaches, depending on your anatomy and body type. A traditional tummy tuck involves an incision that runs from just above the pubic area to just below the navel.</p>



<p>The procedure typically takes between 1-2 hours to complete, depending on whether it&#8217;s a full or partial tummy tuck, as well as how much excess skin needs to be removed.</p>



<p>Tummy Tuck aftercare instructions include:</p>



<p>Avoid strenuous activity for at least 2 weeks following your surgery. This includes exercise, bending or lifting heavy objects or anything else that could put strain on your incisions during this period. If you feel like you are pushing yourself too hard, take it easy!</p>



<p>Avoid sitting in any position that puts pressure on your incision area while it heals; sitting upright is best</p>



<p>Wear loose clothing around your waist area so that it doesn&#8217;t rub against your incision area when you move around (jeans may feel too tight)</p>



<p>The recovery process after a tummy tuck surgery can be a bit challenging, but it&#8217;s important to follow the doctor&#8217;s instructions in order to avoid complications and ensure a successful outcome. If you notice any of these warning signs after your surgery, contact your doctor right away:</p>



<ol>
<li>Dark or bloody drainage from the surgical site</li>



<li>Fever and chills</li>



<li>Redness, swelling or tenderness at the surgical site</li>



<li>Pain that is getting worse or does not go away</li>



<li>A change in bowel or bladder habits</li>
</ol><p>The post <a href="/2023/03/22/how-long-does-swelling-last-after-tummy-tuck-2/">How Long Does Swelling Last After Tummy Tuck</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2023/03/22/how-long-does-swelling-last-after-tummy-tuck-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Can I Have A Baby After A Tummy Tuck</title>
		<link>/2023/03/22/can-i-have-a-baby-after-a-tummy-tuck/</link>
					<comments>/2023/03/22/can-i-have-a-baby-after-a-tummy-tuck/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Ajay Emancipate]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 12:31:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tummy Tuck]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cosmeticsenvogue.com/?p=11173</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Can you have a baby after a tummy tuck? We get this question a lot, and we&#8217;re happy to answer it. The short answer is yes—but there are some important things to consider before deciding whether or not you want to have children after having a tummy tuck. Additionally, if you were planning on breastfeeding...</p>
<p>The post <a href="/2023/03/22/can-i-have-a-baby-after-a-tummy-tuck/">Can I Have A Baby After A Tummy Tuck</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Can you have a baby after a tummy tuck? We get this question a lot, and we&#8217;re happy to answer it. The short answer is yes—but there are some important things to consider before deciding whether or not you want to have children after having a tummy tuck.</p>



<p>Additionally, if you were planning on breastfeeding after having a tummy tuck, you should be aware that breastfeeding can cause stretch marks on the breasts and abdomen. This can affect the appearance of your scars and make them less attractive than before surgery. Also keep in mind that many women find their breasts change after pregnancy because of hormonal changes—this can affect how they feel about their post-surgical results. Finally, if you&#8217;re trying to conceive after having surgery then it&#8217;s important to note that there are potential risks associated with intrauterine insemination (IUI). </p>



<p> Read on to learn more  about Can I Have A Baby After A Tummy Tuck, How Many Sizes Do You Lose With A Tummy Tuck</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="https://cosmeticsurgerytips.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/image-1240.png" alt="" class="wp-image-124276" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Can I Have A Baby After A Tummy Tuck</h2>



<p>There are few life experiences that affect the body as profoundly as carrying a child. For many women, cosmetic surgery is a life-changing solution for restoring a pre-pregnancy body and finally feeling comfortable and confident once again. Without a doubt,&nbsp;tummy tuck&nbsp;surgery is one of the most transformative procedures for women who have had children. If you are interested in enhancing your look and getting rid of loose skin and stubborn fat with a tummy tuck after pregnancy, it is important to understand how a subsequent pregnancy may affect your results.</p>



<p>Renowned board-certified plastic surgeon Dr. Alex Mesbahi and the professional team at Mesbahi Plastic Surgery in McLean, VA understand that every woman’s timeline for having children is different and are committed to helping patients plan their tummy tuck surgery accordingly to ensure the most stunning, longest-lasting results. Learn more about Washington, D.C. tummy tuck surgery here, and find out what factors you should consider when choosing the best time for abdominoplasty.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What does a tummy tuck do?</strong></h2>



<p>A tummy tuck, formally known as abdominoplasty, is a cosmetic body contouring procedure designed to slim, sculpt, and tighten the abdomen primarily through excess skin removal. While a tummy tuck can be beneficial for both men and women, it is exceptionally popular for women as a solution for restoring their pre-baby body. In many cases,&nbsp;liposuction&nbsp;is also performed at the time of abdominoplasty to remove stubborn pockets of fat and further enhance the patient’s results. Some of the most compelling improvements that can be made with tummy tuck surgery include:</p>



<ul>
<li>Loose skin removal</li>



<li>Tighten sagging skin</li>



<li>Get rid of stubborn fat</li>



<li>Restore pre-pregnancy body</li>



<li>Get a smoother, slimmer, firmer midsection</li>



<li>Correct diastasis recti (separated abdominal muscles)</li>



<li>Fix a hernia</li>



<li>Improve urinary continence</li>



<li>Relieve back pain</li>



<li>Boost self-confidence</li>



<li>Fit into clothing more comfortably</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Can I get pregnant after tummy tuck surgery?</strong></h2>



<p>There is no aspect of abdominoplasty surgery that impedes a woman’s ability to conceive, nor is it dangerous to carry a child after having a tummy tuck. Some women report a marked sensation of tightness during pregnancy after tummy tuck, but this is not dangerous to the mother or the fetus. However, patients considering a tummy tuck should understand that a future pregnancy will likely impact their cosmetic outcome and possibly lead to the need for a second or subsequent revision procedure to restore their original results.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>How does pregnancy after tummy tuck affect your results?</strong></h2>



<p>As the womb expands to accommodate the growing fetus during pregnancy, the mother’s abdomen also stretches out. Many women gain about 25 – 35 pounds during pregnancy as well. Once the baby has been delivered, the uterus shrinks back to its original size, and the mother typically loses the majority of her pregnancy weight. However, the skin often remains stretched out and stubborn pockets of fat linger. Furthermore, the abdominal muscles that were tightened during the original tummy tuck procedure may once again become separated, resulting in a recurrent diastasis recti.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>What is the best time to get a tummy tuck?</strong></h2>



<p>During your initial consultation for a tummy tuck in Washington, D.C., Dr. Mesbahi will thoroughly evaluate your concerns, discuss your goals, and explain the procedure in detail. In addition, Dr. Mesbahi will talk with you about your plans to have children in the future. While pregnancy after tummy tuck is certainly safe and possible, women are generally encouraged to defer the procedure until after they are done having children in order to avoid the need for a revision procedure.</p>



<p>However, Dr. Mesbahi understands that life does not always go according to plan and that a woman may change her mind about having additional children. In other cases, women who are many years away from considering children may want to rid themselves of excess stomach skin and enjoy a slimmer look in the meantime. Whatever your timeline for building a family may be, Dr. Mesbahi and his caring team will help you plan your procedure accordingly.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Can I Get Pregnant After a Tummy Tuck?" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VrjdJqGGtBw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How Many Sizes Do You Lose With A Tummy Tuck</h2>



<p>Do you feel self-conscious about loose skin hanging from your abdomen? Have you lost a great deal of weight but still feel unhappy because you now have excess abdominal skin? Do you wish you could lose a bit of belly fat? If so, you may be considered a good candidate for a tummy tuck, also known as abdominoplasty. Today, our aesthetic experts at the office of Dr. Bruce Kadz in Beverly Hills, CA are looking at how many sizes you can lose post-op.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">HOW MANY SIZES DO YOU LOSE WITH A TUMMY TUCK?</h2>



<p>You can generally expect to lose between two and three pants sizes following abdominoplasty. However, if you have a great deal of excess skin and you combine this procedure with liposuction, you may be able to lose four or more pants sizes. We can give you a better idea of how many pants sizes you can expect to lose during your initial consultation. Everyone has a different amount of excess abdominal skin and fat, so individual results vary.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">HOW MUCH WEIGHT CAN YOU LOSE WITH ABDOMINOPLASTY?</h3>



<p>Typically, people lose around five pounds if they get a complete abdominoplasty. If they opt for a partial abdominoplasty, they can expect to lose no more than three pounds. If liposuction is added to a tuck, it is possible to lose closer to 15 pounds. This is because up to 11 pounds of excess fat can be removed safely during most liposuction procedures. The exact amount of fat that can be removed safely depends on one’s starting weight.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">WHAT ARE THE DIFFERENT TYPES OF TUMMY TUCK?&nbsp;</h2>



<p>A complete abdominoplasty, sometimes referred to as a full tuck, is a body contouring procedure that involves improving the appearance of the upper and lower abdomen. This is accomplished by removing excess skin and tightening loose skin below and above the navel. A small amount of excess fat may also be excised during this procedure. An extended tuck is similar, but it also improves the contours of the back and hips.</p>



<p>A partial abdominoplasty, sometimes referred to as a mini tuck, is a body contouring procedure that involves improving the appearance of only the lower abdomen. This procedure may be ideal for you if you do not have concerns about your abdominal walls; the abdominal muscles themselves are only tightened during a full or extended tuck. A bit of excess fat can be excised, but it is not a fat removal procedure.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">HOW LONG WILL MY PROCEDURE TAKE?&nbsp;</h2>



<p>It usually takes around 2.5 hours to perform a full tuck, not including the preparation time or the observation period required after the procedure. All told, if you want to improve the appearance of your upper and lower abdomen, you need to be in our office for roughly 3.5 hours. If you also need quite a bit of excess fat removed, your total appointment time may be closer to 4.5 hours.</p>



<p>We can give you a better idea of how long your procedure will take when you come in for your initial consultation and discuss all of your aesthetic goals. Sometimes, people find that they need other procedures, like an arm lift or liposuction to remove excess chest fat, to achieve their desired aesthetic.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">HOW LONG WILL MY RECOVERY TAKE?</h2>



<p>You can expect most of your recovery to be complete within a week or two of your procedure. This is about how long you will need to take off from work, regardless of whether you get a full tuck, an extended tuck, or a tummy tuck combined with liposuction. How long you have to take off from work depends on how physically demanding your job is and whether your duties can be modified temporarily.</p>



<p>However, you should keep in mind that restrictions will be replaced on your usual activities for six to eight weeks. Specifically, you need to be prepared to take a couple of months off from lifting heavy weights or engaging in any other strenuous physical activity. The more you focus on your rest in the early stages of your recovery, the sooner you will be able to get back to doing what you love safely.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">HOW MUCH SHOULD I DRINK DURING MY RECOVERY PERIOD?</h3>



<p>A good goal to aim for is to drink at least 64 ounces of water and tea daily during your recovery period. However, you should adjust your fluid intake up or down depending on the color of your urine. It should be pale. If it is dark, try drinking more hydrating fluids or snack on a water-dense fruit or vegetable. If it is clear, you are overhydrating and should take a break from drinking for a while.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">SHOULD I EXERCISE AFTER MY PROCEDURE?</h3>



<p>The day after your procedure, you should start making a point to go for gentle walks. However, you should keep in mind while going on your gentle walks that your pulse should not be too elevated, and it is very important to rest whenever your body tells you that it needs rest. It may take a few days before you’re walking like you were before your procedure. Just be patient with yourself, and take as many breaks as you need to.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">HOW MUCH SLEEP SHOULD I TRY TO GET?&nbsp;</h3>



<p>You should try to get nine hours of consecutive sleep each night during your recovery. Usually, adults need around 7.5 hours of sleep per night, but you need a lot more rest during your recovery period because your skin needs to heal itself after the incisions are made. Most of this healing takes place during the rapid eye movement stage of the sleep cycle.</p>



<p>Unfortunately, this is the final stage, and you have to complete all of the earlier stages to get there. If you wake up in the middle of the night, regardless of which stage you were in when you woke up, you have to start over at the first stage of the sleep cycle. If you find that you can’t sleep nine hours in a row, try to get 7.5 hours of consecutive sleep and take a 90-minute nap during the day.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">WHAT SHOULD I EAT AFTER MY PROCEDURE?</h3>



<p>It isn’t just important that you eat fruits and veggies to stay hydrated during your recovery period. It is also important that you eat plenty of protein so your skin can produce enough collagen. Collagen is a protein that is responsible for many functions, including skin tightening and skin healing. Try to get between 50 and 60 grams of protein in your diet every day, and make sure you’re getting your recommended daily allowance of vitamin C.</p>



<p>Protein consumption is crucial because protein is made up of amino acids. Your body can break down protein into usable components (amino acids) and use that material to build the type of protein it needs (collagen). However, you should keep in mind that your body also needs vitamin C to produce collagen. Also, you should make sure you are getting plenty of soluble fiber in your diet. Certain analgesics may affect bowel movements in some people.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">AM I A GOOD CANDIDATE FOR A TUMMY TUCK?</h2>



<p>If you are in fairly good health, there is a good chance that you will qualify for abdominoplasty. However, you must attend an initial evaluation to find out for sure whether this procedure is appropriate for you. If you suffer from certain medical conditions, including heart problems, lung problems, and bleeding disorders, you will not be considered a good candidate for abdominoplasty.</p>



<p>The best candidate for this procedure is an individual who is concerned about the appearance of their abdominal region and does not plan to become pregnant in the future. Often, this procedure is used to repair and tighten the abdominal walls after they have been damaged durign pregnancy or childbirth. A follow-up procedure may be necessary in the future if you become pregnant after getting a tuck.</p><p>The post <a href="/2023/03/22/can-i-have-a-baby-after-a-tummy-tuck/">Can I Have A Baby After A Tummy Tuck</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2023/03/22/can-i-have-a-baby-after-a-tummy-tuck/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>C Section And Tummy Tuck At Same Time</title>
		<link>/2023/03/22/c-section-and-tummy-tuck-at-same-time-2/</link>
					<comments>/2023/03/22/c-section-and-tummy-tuck-at-same-time-2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Ajay Emancipate]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 12:13:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tummy Tuck]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cosmeticsenvogue.com/?p=11155</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Looking for a way to get rid of those stubborn last 5-10 pounds? Or maybe you&#8217;re ready to start your transformation, but you want to make sure you&#8217;re doing it all at once. If so, there&#8217;s no better option than a tummy tuck and liposuction at the same time! The procedure is simple: we remove...</p>
<p>The post <a href="/2023/03/22/c-section-and-tummy-tuck-at-same-time-2/">C Section And Tummy Tuck At Same Time</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Looking for a way to get rid of those stubborn last 5-10 pounds? Or maybe you&#8217;re ready to start your transformation, but you want to make sure you&#8217;re doing it all at once. If so, there&#8217;s no better option than a tummy tuck and liposuction at the same time!</p>



<p>The procedure is simple: we remove the fat from your abdomen and then use it to fill any areas that need plumping up. This means that not only do you have a flat stomach, but you also have a nicer behind and thighs (if desired).</p>



<p>Read on to learn more about C Section And Tummy Tuck At Same Time C Section And Tummy Tuck At Same Time</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/images-prod.healthline.com/hlcmsresource/images/topic_centers/pregnancy/1296x728_Is_it_safe_to_get_a_tummy_tuck_after_a_C-section.jpg?w=1155&amp;h=1528" alt="" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">C Section And Tummy Tuck At Same Time</h2>



<p>A tummy tuck (abdominoplasty) is one of the top five cosmetic surgical procedures in the United States for women ages 30 to 39.</p>



<p>For mothers who are scheduled to have a baby via cesarean delivery, it may seem like combining the birth with a tummy tuck would be ideal. Instead of two separate surgeries, you’d only have one round of anesthetic, one operating room, and one period of recovery. This combination is informally known as a “C-tuck” and it sounds ideal, right?</p>



<p>Well, not exactly. Most doctors would tell you that rolling both surgeries into one isn’t wise. But that doesn’t mean a tummy tuck after you’ve had time to fully recover from a cesarean delivery is out of the question.</p>



<p>Here’s what you should know about getting a tummy tuck after a cesarean delivery, including the best time to consider it.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What’s a tummy tuck?</h2>



<p>It sounds deceptively minimal, but a tummy tuck is actually major surgery. The cosmetic procedure involves cutting and sculpting of muscle, tissue, and skin.</p>



<p>Excess fat and skin is removed. The goal is to restore weakened or separated abdominal muscles. According to the&nbsp;American Society of Plastic Surgeons, a protruding abdomen, or one that is loose or saggy, can be a result of:</p>



<ul>
<li>heredity</li>



<li>a previous surgery</li>



<li>aging</li>



<li>pregnancy</li>



<li>major changes in weight</li>
</ul>



<p>Learning more about what’s involved during and after a tummy tuck (and keeping in mind that it will piggyback your cesarean delivery) is a good way to highlight why combining procedures can be problematic.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What to expect during a tummy tuck</h2>



<p>Before a tummy tuck, you’re given intravenous sedation, or a general aesthetic. A horizontal incision is then made between your bellybutton and the pubic hairline. The precise shape and length of this incision will vary from patient to patient, and it’s related to the amount of excess skin.</p>



<p>Once the incision has been made, the abdominal skin is lifted so that repairs can be made to the muscles below. If there is excess skin in the upper abdomen, a second incision may be necessary.</p>



<p>Next, the abdominal skin is pulled down, trimmed, and sutured together. Your surgeon will create a new opening for your bellybutton, push it through to the surface, and suture that into place. Incisions are closed, and bandages are applied.</p>



<p>You may also have a compression or elastic wrap that’s designed to reduce swelling and provide support to your abdomen during the healing process. In some cases, drainage tubes are also placed beneath the skin to drain blood or fluid.</p>



<p>A full tummy tuck can take anywhere from one to two hours, or longer.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Recovering from a tummy tuck</h2>



<p>Recovering from a tummy tuck usually involves medications to facilitate healing and to reduce the possibility of infection. You’ll also be instructed in how to care for the surgical site and drains if you have them.</p>



<p>There will be required follow-up appointments with your doctor. You’ll also be instructed to minimize any lifting and rest as much as possible.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Problems with combining a tummy tuck and cesarean delivery</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">1. Disappointing results</h3>



<p>The goal of a tummy tuck is to help you look your best. To make that happen, you should be in good physical condition before surgery. After carrying a baby for nine months, both your abdominal skin and your uterus have been impressively stretched. That makes it difficult for a surgeon to accurately determine how much tightening needs to be done. This can lead to disappointing results after you’ve healed.<strong></strong></p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">2. Difficult recovery</h3>



<p>Recovering from a tummy tuck or a cesarean delivery is difficult. Recovering from both surgeries at the same time, on top of caring for a newborn baby, is complicated and exhausting. You’ll be very restricted physically, making things difficult.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">3. Surgeon logistics</h3>



<p>There’s also the matter of finding a plastic surgeon who will agree to perform your tummy tuck immediately after your cesarean delivery. Keep in mind that anything can happen during labor and delivery, and you may find that your carefully scheduled plans don’t work out.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">4. Complications</h3>



<p>Both procedures have risks, and combining them can increase the potential for complications. A woman may be at an increased risk of blood clots and fluid retention. There’s also a greater chance of infection when the uterus is undergoing surgery, as well as the abdominal wall.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What’s the best time for a tummy tuck after a C-section?</h2>



<p>If a tummy tuck is something you’re considering after a cesarean delivery, speak with a certified plastic surgeon. For the best results, you should be back to your original weight and be in good physical condition.</p>



<p>Plan a tummy tuck only if you aren’t planning on becoming pregnant again. Otherwise, you may go through the cost and aggravation of the surgery and recovery only to find your abdomen stretched out again.</p>



<p>Keep in mind that the procedure involves anesthetic and medications. These can be a problem if you’re breast-feeding. Talk to your doctor about what you should and shouldn’t be taking.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Next steps</h2>



<p>There may be benefits to getting a tummy tuck after having a baby. You may be a candidate if you’re physically healthy and your weight has stabilized. But it’s important to allow your body time to heal from both your pregnancy and your cesarean delivery.</p>



<p>You won’t want to miss out on enjoying that early bonding time with your new baby with the added stress of recovery from a tummy tuck.</p>



<p>What is the best time to explore whether a tummy tuck is a good decision for you? After you’re done having children.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="C-section and tummy tuck at the same time &quot;c-tucks&quot;" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/H3yM2yc_vTQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Tummy Tuck After C-section Before And After</h2>



<p>Cesarean sections, commonly called C-sections, currently make up&nbsp;21% of all US births. C-sections are performed for many reasons and are responsible for saving the lives of countless mothers and babies, but they require recovery time and, since they involve the same area of the body, women often wonder how long it will be before it is safe to have&nbsp;tummy tuck surgery&nbsp;to restore their pre-pregnancy body.</p>



<p>In this post, we discuss how long you should wait to have a tummy tuck after your C-section, and why.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>The main reason women undergo tummy tuck surgery following their C-section, however, is to regain their sense of identity and confidence. Pregnancy takes a serious toll on a woman’s body and mind, and restoring her to her former (or enhanced) figure can help her feel more like herself again.</p>
</blockquote>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What are the benefits of getting a tummy tuck after a C-section?</h2>



<p>Because of the incisions made to deliver a baby during a C-section, mothers are left with a large scar running either horizontally or vertically across their lower stomach after giving birth. To address this scar and other physical post-pregnancy changes, many women choose to have tummy tuck surgery, also called abdominoplasty. Following a C-section, tummy tuck surgery can:</p>



<ul>
<li>Lessen the C-section scar and scar tissue</li>



<li>Flatten the tummy by tightening underlying muscles and removing excess fat</li>



<li>Remove any excess skin and the “skin shelf” that sits above the scar</li>



<li>Re-create or even enhance the pre-pregnancy figure</li>



<li>Get rid of abdominal stretch marks</li>



<li>Change your belly button from an ”outie” to an “innie” or otherwise improve its appearance</li>



<li>Repair diastasis recti</li>



<li>Contour the waist</li>
</ul>



<p>The main reason women undergo tummy tuck surgery following their C-section, however, is to regain their sense of identity and confidence. Pregnancy takes a serious toll on a woman’s body and mind, and restoring her to her former (or enhanced) figure can help her feel more like herself again.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why do I need to wait to have a C-section after giving birth?</h2>



<p>For you and your baby, it’s best to wait at least six to 12 months after giving birth to have your tummy tuck. We know this can be difficult if you want to address your C-section scar, loose skin, and extra weight right away, but many moms appreciate waiting for these reasons:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Your body is healing and going through changes:&nbsp;</strong>You’ll need time to heal after pregnancy. Giving birth is physically, emotionally, and mentally taxing! After pregnancy, your body is coping with&nbsp;many postpartum transitions, such as hormonal rebalancing and breast size changes.</li>



<li><strong>Bonding is important:</strong>&nbsp;The first few months following childbirth are critical for mother-child bonding, and waiting for at least six months after giving birth to have your tummy tuck allows you to enjoy this time with your newborn, uninterrupted by an additional surgical recovery.</li>



<li><strong>You need time to plan:</strong>&nbsp;Initial recovery from a tummy tuck takes about two weeks, and you’ll want to make sure that you have time to organize, prepare, and line up the help you’ll need during that period so you can focus on healing.</li>



<li><strong>You won’t be able to lift your child during recovery:</strong>&nbsp;This is not the time to be lifting your child and caring for him or her on your own. If you’re tempted to do so too soon after your tummy tuck, you might accidentally strain your incisions, delay your healing process, or otherwise compromise your results.</li>
</ul>



<p>For more suggestions on recovering from plastic surgery, we invite you to read our&nbsp;Mommy Makeover post.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Can I combine my tummy tuck with my C-section?</h2>



<p>Most doctors strongly advise against combining a tummy tuck with a C-section, as your uterus is still undergoing dramatic size changes in the weeks after childbirth. Additionally, a different anesthesia type is usually used during a C-section versus a tummy tuck (this is because a C-section plan must consider childbirth safety while tummy tuck anesthesia is purely about your comfort). Lastly, your plastic surgeon will be able to recommend a more ideal tummy tuck plan when they can see how much your abdomen has “bounced back” (or not) after carrying your child. All that said, getting a tummy tuck&nbsp;<em>after</em>&nbsp;a C-section is perfectly safe—you just need to give yourself some time.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Will I need drains after my tummy tuck?</h2>



<p>While it is standard for patients to require surgical drains following a tummy tuck, Dr. Claytor offers a&nbsp;drainless, or “no drain,” tummy tuck. When performed properly by a board-certified plastic surgeon, a drainless tummy tuck allows patients to recover faster and with fewer complications.</p>



<p><strong>Here’s how it works:</strong>&nbsp;Dr. Claytor is able to maintain your&nbsp;Scarpa’s fascia&nbsp;(deep connective tissue within your abdominal wall) during surgery, which acts as a natural drainage system for your lymphatic system. This means you won’t have to deal with the hassle of emptying fluids from your drains post-surgery, and because your blood supply is improved and tissue damage is reduced, you’ll heal much faster than a traditional tummy tuck.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Is a drainless tummy tuck safe?</h3>



<p>Traditional tummy tucks remove the lymphatic drainage from the abdomen, necessitating the use of drains. Dr. Claytor’s approach to maintaining your Scarpa’s fascia and lymphatic system is much safer and more natural. His advanced drainless tummy tuck technique has a post-surgical fluid collection rate less than that of patients who use drains, therefore his patients have a much lower rate of developing&nbsp;seromas. Dr. Claytor has been performing drainless tummy tucks with exceptional results for over 10 years in our&nbsp;AAAASF-accredited&nbsp;surgical suite.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">I’m ready to schedule my tummy tuck—what are my next steps?</h2>



<p>Congratulations on your delivery! Now that you are officially recovered from your C-section, you can begin to schedule your tummy tuck procedure. Here’s what you’ll want to do:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Make sure you’re at a stable weight and are in overall good physical condition.&nbsp;</strong>This will ensure you have optimal results from your tummy tuck and will help prevent any potential complications.</li>



<li><strong>Make sure you aren’t planning on becoming pregnant again.</strong>&nbsp;If you do get pregnant after your tummy tuck, you can still safely bear a child, but it will compromise your results. While a secondary tummy tuck can be an option, most women prefer to wait until their family is complete.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Above all else, be sure to consult with a board-certified plastic surgeon.</strong>&nbsp;He or she can let you know if you are a good candidate for surgery.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">C tuck results</h2>



<p><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="536" src="https://www.synergyplasticsurgery.com/content/uploads/2019/12/MAK-Dec19-BlogImage-1024x536.jpg" alt="Woman holding her child"></p>



<p>The “c-tuck” is the latest buzzword to make the rounds in the plastic surgery world, and it’s understandable.&nbsp; The trend, which combines a tummy tuck with a c-section, claims to offer a convenient way to bounce back after a baby without undergoing a separate surgery. Unfortunately, our Austin team of cosmetic&nbsp;body contouring&nbsp;surgery specialists doesn’t recommend this approach, and there are a few major reasons.</p>



<p>Let’s take a look at what the c-tuck trend is all about.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What is a c-tuck?</h2>



<p>A c-tuck is a modified version of a&nbsp;tummy tuck&nbsp;performed at the end of a c-section operation. It’s intended to conveniently offer the benefits of a tummy tuck, primarily abdominal skin tightening, without requiring a separate surgery.</p>



<p>A c-tuck may be performed by a plastic surgeon who is brought in for the procedure. However, some obstetricians offer to create the effect themselves by removing excess skin or improving the appearance of a past c-section scar as they finish the delivery process.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why is the c-tuck a bad idea?</h2>



<p>Sure, coming out of a c-section with a flatter abdomen and avoiding a separate procedure seems great. Unfortunately, it’s usually not the best idea. Here’s why:</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Your results won’t be what you’re looking for.</h3>



<p>By the end of your pregnancy, your skin and muscles are significantly stretched. This makes it difficult to assess how much tightening needs to be done or can be done. After post-delivery swelling goes down and your body recovers from the pregnancy, you’ll probably still have residual loose skin. You won’t get to enjoy the results you would have achieved with a tummy tuck performed at the right time and under the right circumstances.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Your risk of complications is higher.</h3>



<p>You’re not an ideal candidate for a tummy tuck immediately after delivery because your uterus is swollen and your body is undergoing many hormonal changes. This increases your risk for blood clots, infections, and other issues. With a separately scheduled tummy tuck, however, your body will be better prepared, and your surgeon will be able to work in the best possible conditions, keeping your risk for complications as low as possible.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Your recovery will be especially rough.</h3>



<p>Recovering from both a c-section and a major body contouring procedure is complicated and physically demanding. Add a newborn baby into the mix, and it’s easy to see why this recovery situation is not ideal. You’re better off letting your body recuperate from the birth so it’s ready to handle tummy tuck recovery with as much strength and resilience as possible.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How soon can you get a tummy tuck after a c-section?</h2>



<p>A tummy tuck following a c-section certainly isn’t out of the question, but it should be done at the right time for your benefit. It’s best to wait until your weight has stabilized in a healthy range and you have finished breastfeeding.</p>



<p>It’s also wise to make sure your family is complete before you choose a tummy tuck. Future pregnancies can stretch your skin and muscles back out, altering your results.</p>



<p>To see examples of the results you can expect from a tummy tuck at Synergy Plastic Surgery, please visit our&nbsp;before-and-after photo gallery.</p><p>The post <a href="/2023/03/22/c-section-and-tummy-tuck-at-same-time-2/">C Section And Tummy Tuck At Same Time</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2023/03/22/c-section-and-tummy-tuck-at-same-time-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Brazilian Tummy Tuck Cost</title>
		<link>/2023/03/22/brazilian-tummy-tuck-cost-2/</link>
					<comments>/2023/03/22/brazilian-tummy-tuck-cost-2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Ajay Emancipate]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 12:13:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tummy Tuck]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cosmeticsenvogue.com/?p=11151</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Brazilian tummy tuck cost is one of the most popular cosmetic surgery procedures in the world. The cost of Brazilian tummy tuck varies depending on a number of factors including the surgeon, hospital, and area of the country where you live. In this article we will discuss Brazilian Tummy Tuck Costs and how to find...</p>
<p>The post <a href="/2023/03/22/brazilian-tummy-tuck-cost-2/">Brazilian Tummy Tuck Cost</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Brazilian tummy tuck cost is one of the most popular cosmetic surgery procedures in the world. The cost of Brazilian tummy tuck varies depending on a number of factors including the surgeon, hospital, and area of the country where you live. In this article we will discuss Brazilian Tummy Tuck Costs and how to find affordable tummy tucks in Brazil.</p>



<p>Brazilian Tummy Tuck Cost – How Much Does it Cost? The average cost of a Brazilian Tummy Tucker ranges from $3,000 to $10,000 depending on the surgeon’s reputation and credentials as well as the location in which they practice. It’s important to note that these figures are just averages and do not reflect what your specific surgeon may charge for their services. For example: if you visit a top notch plastic surgeon with years of experience under his or her belt then you can expect to pay more than someone who hasn’t had much experience performing these types of procedures yet (although this doesn’t mean they aren’t good at what they do).</p>



<p>Read on to learn more about Brazilian Tummy Tuck Cost, Plastic Surgery Abroad Prices and What Affects the Cost of a Tummy Tuck?</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://www.topdoctors.co.uk/files/Image/large/08897c7b16bdc70d37a21575ff60340a.jpeg" alt="" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Brazilian Tummy Tuck Cost</h2>



<p>The Brazilian Tummy Tuck is a popular procedure for women who want to get rid of the extra skin and fat that accumulates around their tummy after childbirth.</p>



<p>The procedure is also known as the Abdominoplasty, which is a general term for plastic surgery done to improve or reshape the appearance of one&#8217;s abdomen.</p>



<p>Brazilian Tummy Tuck Cost</p>



<p>The cost of Brazilian Tummy Tuck varies according to its complexity and length. The average cost of Brazilian Tummy Tuck in India ranges from $6000 &#8211; $8000. But you can get it done at a much lower price by taking some precautions before choosing your surgeon.</p>



<p>Brazilian Tummy Tuck Cost</p>



<p>The cost of Brazilian Tummy Tuck surgery can vary significantly, depending on the surgeon you choose and whether you have insurance coverage. The average Brazilian Tummy Tuck cost is $5,721, but it can range from $4,500 to $8,000. The average waist-to-hip ratio in Brazil is .72, compared to .79 in the U.S. which indicates that Brazilians tend to have smaller waists than Americans. This may be due to genetics or possibly because people in other countries tend not to eat as much junk food as Americans do.</p>



<p>Brazilian Tummy Tuck Cost</p>



<p>The Brazilian Tummy Tuck Cost is $5,000 to $7,000. The cost will vary depending on the surgeon and the procedure. The Brazilian Tummy Tuck costs less than other types of abdominal surgery because there is less skin to remove and the incision is smaller.</p>



<p>Brazilian Butt Lift Cost</p>



<p>The Brazilian Butt Lift Cost is $6,500 to $10,000. The cost will vary depending on the surgeon and the procedure. The Brazilian Butt Lift costs less than other types of body contouring surgery because there is less fat grafting needed to get results that look natural.</p>



<p>Buttock Augmentation Cost</p>



<p>The Buttock Augmentation Cost is $2,500 to $3,500 per buttock (both sides). The cost will vary depending on the surgeon and the procedure. The Buttock Augmentation costs less than other types of body contouring surgery because there is less fat grafting needed for a natural-looking result</p>



<p>The Brazilian Tummy Tuck cost is dependent on a number of factors, including the type of procedure you choose and how much your medical insurance will cover.</p>



<p>The average Brazilian Tummy Tuck price is $5,500. This figure includes the surgeon fee, anesthesia fee, and hospital or surgical center fee.</p>



<p>Some surgeons may charge more than this average because their experience level is higher or because they practice in an area with higher costs of living. Other surgeons may charge less than average because they have a lower-than-average operating room fees or because they offer discounts for paying in full within a certain timeframe after surgery.</p>



<p>If your insurance covers plastic surgery, you may be responsible for paying only your portion of the deductible (typically $100-$200) and coinsurance (typically 20%-35%). If your insurance does not cover plastic surgery, then you may be responsible for paying the entire cost of your procedure up front before undergoing any work at all.</p>



<p>The cost of a Brazilian Tummy Tuck will depend on a variety of factors such as experience of the surgeon and the complexity of the procedure. A typical tummy tuck surgery will cost between £6000 and £8000. The price may vary depending on whether you choose to have general anaesthetic or local anaesthetic.</p>



<p>Before undergoing surgery, you should ask your surgeon how much they charge for the procedure and how many operations they perform each year. This will give you an idea of the quality of their work and whether or not they are experienced enough to perform your surgery.</p>



<p>The cost can also vary depending on whether you choose to have general anaesthetic or local anaesthetic. You should also factor in travel expenses if your surgeon is located far away from where you live.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="What is the Brazilian Tummy Tuck Abdomnioplasty Technique?" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1z4l7eCu9ck?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Plastic Surgery Abroad Prices</h2>



<p>The right plastic surgery procedure could make you look—and feel—like perfection. But taking the time to do your research is key, as there are renowned and talented plastic surgeons all over the world who can help you look your absolute best at an affordable price. It’s no wonder that so many people are choosing to undergo a variety of plastic surgery procedures in another country.<br>&nbsp;<br>If you have been thinking about plastic surgery but the doctors in your home country are too expensive, or if you are hoping to find the absolute best doctor and medical facility for your needs, looking abroad could be a wise move. This guide to plastic surgery abroad can help steer your decisions as you do your research.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What you should consider before undergoing plastic surgery abroad</h2>



<p>Before you dive right into finding the&nbsp;best place for cosmetic surgery abroad, you will need to take a few factors into consideration. Doing so will help you make the right choices for your health, and it will also help guide you to the appropriate overseas destination and medical facility that will perform the surgery with utmost care and precision.<br><br>There are many countries where plastic surgery procedures are commonplace and where medical professionals have honed their skills so they can provide their patients with top-notch care and beautiful results. Narrowing down those choices will involve taking a few concerns into consideration.</p>



<p><strong>Don’t just focus on price</strong><br>Sure, you can get a great deal on an otherwise really expensive plastic surgery procedure abroad, but price should not be your only decision maker. After all, even when you source your medical specialist abroad, you should expect to pay more for someone with many years of experience versus and newly graduated practitioner. While you can certainly think about cost and factor it into your final decision, it should not be your be-all and end-all for your ultimate choice.</p>



<p><strong>Research the conditions of a clinic before booking</strong><br>Not all plastic surgery clinics are created equal, both at home and abroad. Online photos may not give you an accurate representation of the clinic, as they may be outdated. If at all possible, it is highly recommended that you visit a clinic prior to actually booking your surgery. Ask for a tour of the facility, talk to the staff, and make a preliminary appointment to talk with the doctor. And don’t forget to ask to see certification information to be certain that the hospital or clinic is fully accredited, as that will prove that it has passed a comprehensive review and that it operates in a manner that focuses on patient safety.</p>



<p><strong>Ensure that the surgeon is fully qualified</strong><br>Different countries will have different requirements for medical certifications, so when you look abroad, you may encounter surgeons who are not as qualified as those at home. So, in addition to looking into the conditions of the facility, also ask about the surgeon’s educational background. Many highly qualified surgeons abroad will be able to prove that they were actually trained in the United States or in the United Kingdom, as a couple of examples, so they will be certified by the American Medical Association (AMA) or the General Medical Council (GMC), respectively. European accreditation bodies, such as the European Association of Plastic Surgeons, as well as international bodies, like the International Society of Aesthetic Plastic Surgery (ISAPS) or the International Confederation for Plastic, Reconstructive and Aesthetic Surgery (IPRAS), can also provide you with additional peace of mind regarding the qualifications of the medical facility and its staff..</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="091e9c5e821d5a0a-1-4">What Affects the Cost of a Tummy Tuck?</h2>



<p>Many factors come into play when determining the cost of a tummy tuck.<strong>‌</strong></p>



<p><strong>The extent of the procedure.</strong>&nbsp;In some cases, all that is involved in a tummy tuck is tightening the loose, sagging skin below the navel. However, the process is customizable to meet your needs and preferences. Depending on how much work the surgeon has to do, the procedure can either be a full, mini, or extended tummy tuck.&nbsp;<strong>‌</strong></p>



<p>A mini tummy tuck that only addresses the loose skin may cost between $4,000 and $5,000. A traditional tummy tuck may cost between $8,000 and $10,000, while an extended tummy job may be worth up to $20,000.<strong>‌</strong></p>



<p><strong>The size of the area.</strong>&nbsp;If the procedure only entails tightening loose skin and eliminating fat from the lower abdomen, the cost will be relatively low. However, when you need a full tummy tuck, the procedure’s scope calls for more expenses. This is because it involves both the upper and lower abdomen. Extended tummy tucks are also more expensive because they involve the front side, back, and sides.</p>



<p><strong>The volume of fat removed.</strong>&nbsp;The extent of the procedure can be fat removal, muscle tightening, skin lifting and tightening, and muscle reshaping or repairing. The more services you get during the process, the higher the cost will be.</p>



<p><strong>The type of anesthesia used.</strong>&nbsp;The type and dosage of anesthesia you receive during a tummy tuck is another significant factor that affects the procedure’s cost. If you require a larger dose of anesthesia depending on the extent of the surgery, the price will be higher.&nbsp;</p>



<p>General anesthesia is usually more expensive than local anesthesia. The reason for this is that with local anesthesia, you may also have to take a sedative to help you sleep through the procedure, hence a lower dose. The cost of general anesthesia is between $425 and $1,800, while that of local anesthesia is between $500 and $3,500.</p>



<p><strong>The number of procedures to be performed.</strong>&nbsp;In some cases, lifting and tightening your stomach skin is not enough to help you achieve your ideal aesthetic level. As such, you may be a good candidate for an extra procedure. Doing so will help to contour your body by removing excess fat. Liposuction is usually an ideal complementary procedure to tummy tuck as it draws more fat than a tummy tuck.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="091e9c5e821d5a0a-3-8">Preparing for a Tummy Tuck</h2>



<p>Before you go in for a tummy tuck, your doctor may schedule you for a blood panel to ensure you’re in good health. You will also be required to:</p>



<ul>
<li>Stop&nbsp;smoking</li>



<li>Limit your alcohol intake</li>



<li>Stop taking&nbsp;anti-inflammatory drugs&nbsp;and some herbal supplements that can make bleeding worse or hinder clotting.</li>
</ul><p>The post <a href="/2023/03/22/brazilian-tummy-tuck-cost-2/">Brazilian Tummy Tuck Cost</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2023/03/22/brazilian-tummy-tuck-cost-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>C Section And Tummy Tuck At Same Time</title>
		<link>/2023/03/22/c-section-and-tummy-tuck-at-same-time/</link>
					<comments>/2023/03/22/c-section-and-tummy-tuck-at-same-time/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Ajay Emancipate]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 11:52:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tummy Tuck]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cosmeticsenvogue.com/?p=11120</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Looking for a way to get rid of those stubborn last 5-10 pounds? Or maybe you&#8217;re ready to start your transformation, but you want to make sure you&#8217;re doing it all at once. If so, there&#8217;s no better option than a tummy tuck and liposuction at the same time! The procedure is simple: we remove...</p>
<p>The post <a href="/2023/03/22/c-section-and-tummy-tuck-at-same-time/">C Section And Tummy Tuck At Same Time</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Looking for a way to get rid of those stubborn last 5-10 pounds? Or maybe you&#8217;re ready to start your transformation, but you want to make sure you&#8217;re doing it all at once. If so, there&#8217;s no better option than a tummy tuck and liposuction at the same time!</p>



<p>The procedure is simple: we remove the fat from your abdomen and then use it to fill any areas that need plumping up. This means that not only do you have a flat stomach, but you also have a nicer behind and thighs (if desired).</p>



<p>Read on to learn more about C Section And Tummy Tuck At Same Time C Section And Tummy Tuck At Same Time</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/images-prod.healthline.com/hlcmsresource/images/topic_centers/pregnancy/1296x728_Is_it_safe_to_get_a_tummy_tuck_after_a_C-section.jpg?w=1155&amp;h=1528" alt="" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">C Section And Tummy Tuck At Same Time</h2>



<p>A tummy tuck (abdominoplasty) is one of the top five cosmetic surgical procedures in the United States for women ages 30 to 39.</p>



<p>For mothers who are scheduled to have a baby via cesarean delivery, it may seem like combining the birth with a tummy tuck would be ideal. Instead of two separate surgeries, you’d only have one round of anesthetic, one operating room, and one period of recovery. This combination is informally known as a “C-tuck” and it sounds ideal, right?</p>



<p>Well, not exactly. Most doctors would tell you that rolling both surgeries into one isn’t wise. But that doesn’t mean a tummy tuck after you’ve had time to fully recover from a cesarean delivery is out of the question.</p>



<p>Here’s what you should know about getting a tummy tuck after a cesarean delivery, including the best time to consider it.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What’s a tummy tuck?</h2>



<p>It sounds deceptively minimal, but a tummy tuck is actually major surgery. The cosmetic procedure involves cutting and sculpting of muscle, tissue, and skin.</p>



<p>Excess fat and skin is removed. The goal is to restore weakened or separated abdominal muscles. According to the&nbsp;American Society of Plastic Surgeons, a protruding abdomen, or one that is loose or saggy, can be a result of:</p>



<ul>
<li>heredity</li>



<li>a previous surgery</li>



<li>aging</li>



<li>pregnancy</li>



<li>major changes in weight</li>
</ul>



<p>Learning more about what’s involved during and after a tummy tuck (and keeping in mind that it will piggyback your cesarean delivery) is a good way to highlight why combining procedures can be problematic.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What to expect during a tummy tuck</h2>



<p>Before a tummy tuck, you’re given intravenous sedation, or a general aesthetic. A horizontal incision is then made between your bellybutton and the pubic hairline. The precise shape and length of this incision will vary from patient to patient, and it’s related to the amount of excess skin.</p>



<p>Once the incision has been made, the abdominal skin is lifted so that repairs can be made to the muscles below. If there is excess skin in the upper abdomen, a second incision may be necessary.</p>



<p>Next, the abdominal skin is pulled down, trimmed, and sutured together. Your surgeon will create a new opening for your bellybutton, push it through to the surface, and suture that into place. Incisions are closed, and bandages are applied.</p>



<p>You may also have a compression or elastic wrap that’s designed to reduce swelling and provide support to your abdomen during the healing process. In some cases, drainage tubes are also placed beneath the skin to drain blood or fluid.</p>



<p>A full tummy tuck can take anywhere from one to two hours, or longer.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Recovering from a tummy tuck</h2>



<p>Recovering from a tummy tuck usually involves medications to facilitate healing and to reduce the possibility of infection. You’ll also be instructed in how to care for the surgical site and drains if you have them.</p>



<p>There will be required follow-up appointments with your doctor. You’ll also be instructed to minimize any lifting and rest as much as possible.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Problems with combining a tummy tuck and cesarean delivery</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">1. Disappointing results</h3>



<p>The goal of a tummy tuck is to help you look your best. To make that happen, you should be in good physical condition before surgery. After carrying a baby for nine months, both your abdominal skin and your uterus have been impressively stretched. That makes it difficult for a surgeon to accurately determine how much tightening needs to be done. This can lead to disappointing results after you’ve healed.<strong></strong></p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">2. Difficult recovery</h3>



<p>Recovering from a tummy tuck or a cesarean delivery is difficult. Recovering from both surgeries at the same time, on top of caring for a newborn baby, is complicated and exhausting. You’ll be very restricted physically, making things difficult.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">3. Surgeon logistics</h3>



<p>There’s also the matter of finding a plastic surgeon who will agree to perform your tummy tuck immediately after your cesarean delivery. Keep in mind that anything can happen during labor and delivery, and you may find that your carefully scheduled plans don’t work out.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">4. Complications</h3>



<p>Both procedures have risks, and combining them can increase the potential for complications. A woman may be at an increased risk of blood clots and fluid retention. There’s also a greater chance of infection when the uterus is undergoing surgery, as well as the abdominal wall.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What’s the best time for a tummy tuck after a C-section?</h2>



<p>If a tummy tuck is something you’re considering after a cesarean delivery, speak with a certified plastic surgeon. For the best results, you should be back to your original weight and be in good physical condition.</p>



<p>Plan a tummy tuck only if you aren’t planning on becoming pregnant again. Otherwise, you may go through the cost and aggravation of the surgery and recovery only to find your abdomen stretched out again.</p>



<p>Keep in mind that the procedure involves anesthetic and medications. These can be a problem if you’re breast-feeding. Talk to your doctor about what you should and shouldn’t be taking.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Next steps</h2>



<p>There may be benefits to getting a tummy tuck after having a baby. You may be a candidate if you’re physically healthy and your weight has stabilized. But it’s important to allow your body time to heal from both your pregnancy and your cesarean delivery.</p>



<p>You won’t want to miss out on enjoying that early bonding time with your new baby with the added stress of recovery from a tummy tuck.</p>



<p>What is the best time to explore whether a tummy tuck is a good decision for you? After you’re done having children.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="C-section and tummy tuck at the same time &quot;c-tucks&quot;" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/H3yM2yc_vTQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Tummy Tuck After C-section Before And After</h2>



<p>Cesarean sections, commonly called C-sections, currently make up&nbsp;21% of all US births. C-sections are performed for many reasons and are responsible for saving the lives of countless mothers and babies, but they require recovery time and, since they involve the same area of the body, women often wonder how long it will be before it is safe to have&nbsp;tummy tuck surgery&nbsp;to restore their pre-pregnancy body.</p>



<p>In this post, we discuss how long you should wait to have a tummy tuck after your C-section, and why.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>The main reason women undergo tummy tuck surgery following their C-section, however, is to regain their sense of identity and confidence. Pregnancy takes a serious toll on a woman’s body and mind, and restoring her to her former (or enhanced) figure can help her feel more like herself again.</p>
</blockquote>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What are the benefits of getting a tummy tuck after a C-section?</h2>



<p>Because of the incisions made to deliver a baby during a C-section, mothers are left with a large scar running either horizontally or vertically across their lower stomach after giving birth. To address this scar and other physical post-pregnancy changes, many women choose to have tummy tuck surgery, also called abdominoplasty. Following a C-section, tummy tuck surgery can:</p>



<ul>
<li>Lessen the C-section scar and scar tissue</li>



<li>Flatten the tummy by tightening underlying muscles and removing excess fat</li>



<li>Remove any excess skin and the “skin shelf” that sits above the scar</li>



<li>Re-create or even enhance the pre-pregnancy figure</li>



<li>Get rid of abdominal stretch marks</li>



<li>Change your belly button from an ”outie” to an “innie” or otherwise improve its appearance</li>



<li>Repair diastasis recti</li>



<li>Contour the waist</li>
</ul>



<p>The main reason women undergo tummy tuck surgery following their C-section, however, is to regain their sense of identity and confidence. Pregnancy takes a serious toll on a woman’s body and mind, and restoring her to her former (or enhanced) figure can help her feel more like herself again.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why do I need to wait to have a C-section after giving birth?</h2>



<p>For you and your baby, it’s best to wait at least six to 12 months after giving birth to have your tummy tuck. We know this can be difficult if you want to address your C-section scar, loose skin, and extra weight right away, but many moms appreciate waiting for these reasons:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Your body is healing and going through changes:&nbsp;</strong>You’ll need time to heal after pregnancy. Giving birth is physically, emotionally, and mentally taxing! After pregnancy, your body is coping with&nbsp;many postpartum transitions, such as hormonal rebalancing and breast size changes.</li>



<li><strong>Bonding is important:</strong>&nbsp;The first few months following childbirth are critical for mother-child bonding, and waiting for at least six months after giving birth to have your tummy tuck allows you to enjoy this time with your newborn, uninterrupted by an additional surgical recovery.</li>



<li><strong>You need time to plan:</strong>&nbsp;Initial recovery from a tummy tuck takes about two weeks, and you’ll want to make sure that you have time to organize, prepare, and line up the help you’ll need during that period so you can focus on healing.</li>



<li><strong>You won’t be able to lift your child during recovery:</strong>&nbsp;This is not the time to be lifting your child and caring for him or her on your own. If you’re tempted to do so too soon after your tummy tuck, you might accidentally strain your incisions, delay your healing process, or otherwise compromise your results.</li>
</ul>



<p>For more suggestions on recovering from plastic surgery, we invite you to read our&nbsp;Mommy Makeover post.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Can I combine my tummy tuck with my C-section?</h2>



<p>Most doctors strongly advise against combining a tummy tuck with a C-section, as your uterus is still undergoing dramatic size changes in the weeks after childbirth. Additionally, a different anesthesia type is usually used during a C-section versus a tummy tuck (this is because a C-section plan must consider childbirth safety while tummy tuck anesthesia is purely about your comfort). Lastly, your plastic surgeon will be able to recommend a more ideal tummy tuck plan when they can see how much your abdomen has “bounced back” (or not) after carrying your child. All that said, getting a tummy tuck&nbsp;<em>after</em>&nbsp;a C-section is perfectly safe—you just need to give yourself some time.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Will I need drains after my tummy tuck?</h2>



<p>While it is standard for patients to require surgical drains following a tummy tuck, Dr. Claytor offers a&nbsp;drainless, or “no drain,” tummy tuck. When performed properly by a board-certified plastic surgeon, a drainless tummy tuck allows patients to recover faster and with fewer complications.</p>



<p><strong>Here’s how it works:</strong>&nbsp;Dr. Claytor is able to maintain your&nbsp;Scarpa’s fascia&nbsp;(deep connective tissue within your abdominal wall) during surgery, which acts as a natural drainage system for your lymphatic system. This means you won’t have to deal with the hassle of emptying fluids from your drains post-surgery, and because your blood supply is improved and tissue damage is reduced, you’ll heal much faster than a traditional tummy tuck.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Is a drainless tummy tuck safe?</h3>



<p>Traditional tummy tucks remove the lymphatic drainage from the abdomen, necessitating the use of drains. Dr. Claytor’s approach to maintaining your Scarpa’s fascia and lymphatic system is much safer and more natural. His advanced drainless tummy tuck technique has a post-surgical fluid collection rate less than that of patients who use drains, therefore his patients have a much lower rate of developing&nbsp;seromas. Dr. Claytor has been performing drainless tummy tucks with exceptional results for over 10 years in our&nbsp;AAAASF-accredited&nbsp;surgical suite.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">I’m ready to schedule my tummy tuck—what are my next steps?</h2>



<p>Congratulations on your delivery! Now that you are officially recovered from your C-section, you can begin to schedule your tummy tuck procedure. Here’s what you’ll want to do:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Make sure you’re at a stable weight and are in overall good physical condition.&nbsp;</strong>This will ensure you have optimal results from your tummy tuck and will help prevent any potential complications.</li>



<li><strong>Make sure you aren’t planning on becoming pregnant again.</strong>&nbsp;If you do get pregnant after your tummy tuck, you can still safely bear a child, but it will compromise your results. While a secondary tummy tuck can be an option, most women prefer to wait until their family is complete.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Above all else, be sure to consult with a board-certified plastic surgeon.</strong>&nbsp;He or she can let you know if you are a good candidate for surgery.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">C tuck results</h2>



<p><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="536" src="https://www.synergyplasticsurgery.com/content/uploads/2019/12/MAK-Dec19-BlogImage-1024x536.jpg" alt="Woman holding her child"></p>



<p>The “c-tuck” is the latest buzzword to make the rounds in the plastic surgery world, and it’s understandable.&nbsp; The trend, which combines a tummy tuck with a c-section, claims to offer a convenient way to bounce back after a baby without undergoing a separate surgery. Unfortunately, our Austin team of cosmetic&nbsp;body contouring&nbsp;surgery specialists doesn’t recommend this approach, and there are a few major reasons.</p>



<p>Let’s take a look at what the c-tuck trend is all about.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What is a c-tuck?</h2>



<p>A c-tuck is a modified version of a&nbsp;tummy tuck&nbsp;performed at the end of a c-section operation. It’s intended to conveniently offer the benefits of a tummy tuck, primarily abdominal skin tightening, without requiring a separate surgery.</p>



<p>A c-tuck may be performed by a plastic surgeon who is brought in for the procedure. However, some obstetricians offer to create the effect themselves by removing excess skin or improving the appearance of a past c-section scar as they finish the delivery process.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why is the c-tuck a bad idea?</h2>



<p>Sure, coming out of a c-section with a flatter abdomen and avoiding a separate procedure seems great. Unfortunately, it’s usually not the best idea. Here’s why:</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Your results won’t be what you’re looking for.</h3>



<p>By the end of your pregnancy, your skin and muscles are significantly stretched. This makes it difficult to assess how much tightening needs to be done or can be done. After post-delivery swelling goes down and your body recovers from the pregnancy, you’ll probably still have residual loose skin. You won’t get to enjoy the results you would have achieved with a tummy tuck performed at the right time and under the right circumstances.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Your risk of complications is higher.</h3>



<p>You’re not an ideal candidate for a tummy tuck immediately after delivery because your uterus is swollen and your body is undergoing many hormonal changes. This increases your risk for blood clots, infections, and other issues. With a separately scheduled tummy tuck, however, your body will be better prepared, and your surgeon will be able to work in the best possible conditions, keeping your risk for complications as low as possible.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Your recovery will be especially rough.</h3>



<p>Recovering from both a c-section and a major body contouring procedure is complicated and physically demanding. Add a newborn baby into the mix, and it’s easy to see why this recovery situation is not ideal. You’re better off letting your body recuperate from the birth so it’s ready to handle tummy tuck recovery with as much strength and resilience as possible.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How soon can you get a tummy tuck after a c-section?</h2>



<p>A tummy tuck following a c-section certainly isn’t out of the question, but it should be done at the right time for your benefit. It’s best to wait until your weight has stabilized in a healthy range and you have finished breastfeeding.</p>



<p>It’s also wise to make sure your family is complete before you choose a tummy tuck. Future pregnancies can stretch your skin and muscles back out, altering your results.</p>



<p>To see examples of the results you can expect from a tummy tuck at Synergy Plastic Surgery, please visit our&nbsp;before-and-after photo gallery.</p><p>The post <a href="/2023/03/22/c-section-and-tummy-tuck-at-same-time/">C Section And Tummy Tuck At Same Time</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2023/03/22/c-section-and-tummy-tuck-at-same-time/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Brazil Tummy Tuck Prices</title>
		<link>/2023/03/22/brazil-tummy-tuck-prices/</link>
					<comments>/2023/03/22/brazil-tummy-tuck-prices/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Ajay Emancipate]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 11:51:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tummy Tuck]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cosmeticsenvogue.com/?p=11094</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Brazil tummy tuck prices Brazil is a beautiful country with many things to see and do. If you are planning a trip to Brazil, you might be interested in getting a tummy tuck while you are there. Here is some information about the cost of the procedure in Brazil, as well as what it will...</p>
<p>The post <a href="/2023/03/22/brazil-tummy-tuck-prices/">Brazil Tummy Tuck Prices</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Brazil tummy tuck prices Brazil is a beautiful country with many things to see and do. If you are planning a trip to Brazil, you might be interested in getting a tummy tuck while you are there. Here is some information about the cost of the procedure in Brazil, as well as what it will cost you for other services that may be offered during your trip.</p>



<p>Tummy Tucks in Brazil The average price of a tummy tuck in Brazil is $5,000 USD. However, this does not include any other services that may be included with your procedure such as liposuction or breast augmentation. If you want to add these services onto your surgery then the price can increase by another $2,000 USD on average.</p>



<p>Read on to learn more about Brazil Tummy Tuck Prices</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Brazil Tummy Tuck Prices</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://cosmeticsurgerytips.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/image-535.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-11217" width="612" height="490" /></figure>



<p>The Brazilian Buttock Lift and Tummy Tuck cost is dependent on the area that is being treated. The cost of Brazilian Buttock Lift and Tummy Tuck in Brazil is around $3,500. The price may vary depending on the area that needs treatment, but the average price of a Brazilian Buttock Lift and Tummy Tuck in Brazil is between $2,500 and $5,000.</p>



<p>Brazilian Buttock Lift And Tummy Tuck Cost</p>



<p>Brazilian Butt Lift and Tummy Tuck Cost in Brazil is $5,000 to $8,000. This includes the cost of the surgery, anesthesia, and hospital stay. The procedure takes about 1 hour to perform and is done under general anesthesia. Patients who have excess skin around the waistline after losing weight or undergoing other surgeries are good candidates for this procedure.</p>



<p>The cost of Brazilian buttock lift and tummy tuck will vary depending on where it is performed and whether any other procedures are done at the same time. It’s also important to consider any additional costs that may arise from complications with anesthesia or infections post-surgery.</p>



<p>Brazilian Buttock Lift and Tummy Tuck Cost</p>



<p>Brazilian Butt Lift and Tummy Tuck Prices</p>



<p>Brazilian Butt Lift and Tummy Tuck Cost in Brazil:</p>



<p>The costs of the Brazilian butt lift and tummy tuck vary depending on the surgeon, clinic, and type of procedure. The average cost for a Brazilian butt lift is around $1,500 to $6,000. The average cost for a Brazilian butt lift with implants is around $2,500 to $10,000. The average cost for a tummy tuck with liposuction is around $3,500 to $8,000.</p>



<p>The price will be determined by several factors including:</p>



<p>Surgeon’s experience level</p>



<p>Type of procedure performed (i.e., fat transfer vs. liposuction)</p>



<p>A Brazilian butt lift and tummy tuck cost varies depending on the surgeon, geographical location, and the overall health of the patient.</p>



<p>Brazilian Butt Lift And Tummy Tuck Cost: $7,500 &#8211; $13,000</p>



<p>In general, a Brazilian butt lift and tummy tuck cost ranges from $7,500 to $13,000. The average price for Brazilian butt lift and tummy tuck is about $10,500.</p>



<p>The cost of a Brazilian butt lift and tummy tuck procedure varies by geographic location because of differences in local labor costs. For example, the average cost for a Brazilian butt lift and tummy tuck in Miami is about $11,000 while it&#8217;s about $9,500 in New York City.</p>



<p>Brazil is one of the best destinations for cosmetic surgery. The country has some of the best surgeons and clinics in the world. You can have a great time here and get your dream body at an affordable price.</p>



<p>Brazil Buttock Lift And Tummy Tuck Cost</p>



<p>Brazilian buttock lift and tummy tuck cost may vary depending on your choice of surgeon, location, facility and other factors. The average cost of these procedures can be anywhere between $7,500 to $15,000 USD. But it can go up depending on the complexity of your case and additional procedures you need such as breast augmentation or nose job.</p>



<p>Brazilian Buttock Lift And Brazilian Tummy Tuck – Average Price</p>



<p>The average price for both procedures is $9000 USD which includes costs from consultation to post-operative care; however, this is just an estimate because many factors affect the final price like time spent in hospital or recovery time required after surgery etc.</p>



<p>You should also take into account that this amount excludes travel expenses as well as hotel stay during recovery period which can vary from one clinic to another; so it&#8217;s always better if you plan ahead before making any decision regarding surgery abroad</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Should I Get a Tummy Tuck or a BBL" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/mtRJFTDeYNQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="091e9c5e821d5a0a-1-2">What is a Mini Tummy Tuck?</h2>



<p>A tummy tuck, also known as abdominoplasty, refers to a surgical procedure that alters the&nbsp;abdominal&nbsp;skin, soft tissues, and fat. It doesn’t affect the abdominal muscles. Tummy tucks are used for the lower abdomen and also to contour the body into the desired shape. The procedure is ideal for people within their recommended weight range but who have an extra layer of skin or fat that they need to address.<strong>‌</strong></p>



<p>During the procedure, the specialist attending to you joins the tissues in your lower abdomen together. The results of the surgery are not visible from the outside. They also trim the excess skin and lay it flat. Depending on how much fat is in the area, the specialist will also perform&nbsp;liposuction&nbsp;to remove any excess fat.<strong>‌</strong></p>



<p>In some cases, a mini tummy tuck can get rid of certain&nbsp;stretch marks. However, their removal depends on their placement on your body and how much excess skin you have.<strong>‌</strong></p>



<p>In cases of&nbsp;diastasis recti, which is the separation of&nbsp;ab muscles, a full tummy tuck is a better option. The condition mostly happens during pregnancy, affecting the entire area above and below the&nbsp;navel.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="091e9c5e821d5a0a-1-4">What Affects the Cost of a Tummy Tuck?</h2>



<p>Many factors come into play when determining the cost of a tummy tuck.<strong>‌</strong></p>



<p><strong>The extent of the procedure.</strong>&nbsp;In some cases, all that is involved in a tummy tuck is tightening the loose, sagging skin below the navel. However, the process is customizable to meet your needs and preferences. Depending on how much work the surgeon has to do, the procedure can either be a full, mini, or extended tummy tuck.&nbsp;<strong>‌</strong></p>



<p>A mini tummy tuck that only addresses the loose skin may cost between $4,000 and $5,000. A traditional tummy tuck may cost between $8,000 and $10,000, while an extended tummy job may be worth up to $20,000.<strong>‌</strong></p>



<p><strong>The size of the area.</strong>&nbsp;If the procedure only entails tightening loose skin and eliminating fat from the lower abdomen, the cost will be relatively low. However, when you need a full tummy tuck, the procedure’s scope calls for more expenses. This is because it involves both the upper and lower abdomen. Extended tummy tucks are also more expensive because they involve the front side, back, and sides.</p>



<p><strong>The volume of fat removed.</strong>&nbsp;The extent of the procedure can be fat removal, muscle tightening, skin lifting and tightening, and muscle reshaping or repairing. The more services you get during the process, the higher the cost will be.</p>



<p><strong>The type of anesthesia used.</strong>&nbsp;The type and dosage of anesthesia you receive during a tummy tuck is another significant factor that affects the procedure’s cost. If you require a larger dose of anesthesia depending on the extent of the surgery, the price will be higher.&nbsp;</p>



<p>General anesthesia is usually more expensive than local anesthesia. The reason for this is that with local anesthesia, you may also have to take a sedative to help you sleep through the procedure, hence a lower dose. The cost of general anesthesia is between $425 and $1,800, while that of local anesthesia is between $500 and $3,500.</p>



<p><strong>The number of procedures to be performed.</strong>&nbsp;In some cases, lifting and tightening your stomach skin is not enough to help you achieve your ideal aesthetic level. As such, you may be a good candidate for an extra procedure. Doing so will help to contour your body by removing excess fat. Liposuction is usually an ideal complementary procedure to tummy tuck as it draws more fat than a tummy tuck.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="091e9c5e821d5a0a-3-8">Preparing for a Tummy Tuck</h2>



<p>Before you go in for a tummy tuck, your doctor may schedule you for a blood panel to ensure you’re in good health. You will also be required to:</p>



<ul>
<li>Stop&nbsp;smoking</li>



<li>Limit your alcohol intake</li>



<li>Stop taking&nbsp;anti-inflammatory drugs&nbsp;and some herbal supplements that can make bleeding worse or hinder clotting.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Brazilian Tummy Tuck Cost</h2>



<p>The Brazilian Tummy Tuck is a popular procedure for women who want to get rid of the extra skin and fat that accumulates around their tummy after childbirth.</p>



<p>The procedure is also known as the Abdominoplasty, which is a general term for plastic surgery done to improve or reshape the appearance of one&#8217;s abdomen.</p>



<p>Brazilian Tummy Tuck Cost</p>



<p>The cost of Brazilian Tummy Tuck varies according to its complexity and length. The average cost of Brazilian Tummy Tuck in India ranges from $6000 &#8211; $8000. But you can get it done at a much lower price by taking some precautions before choosing your surgeon.</p>



<p>Brazilian Tummy Tuck Cost</p>



<p>The cost of Brazilian Tummy Tuck surgery can vary significantly, depending on the surgeon you choose and whether you have insurance coverage. The average Brazilian Tummy Tuck cost is $5,721, but it can range from $4,500 to $8,000. The average waist-to-hip ratio in Brazil is .72, compared to .79 in the U.S. which indicates that Brazilians tend to have smaller waists than Americans. This may be due to genetics or possibly because people in other countries tend not to eat as much junk food as Americans do.</p>



<p>Brazilian Tummy Tuck Cost</p>



<p>The Brazilian Tummy Tuck Cost is $5,000 to $7,000. The cost will vary depending on the surgeon and the procedure. The Brazilian Tummy Tuck costs less than other types of abdominal surgery because there is less skin to remove and the incision is smaller.</p>



<p>Brazilian Butt Lift Cost</p>



<p>The Brazilian Butt Lift Cost is $6,500 to $10,000. The cost will vary depending on the surgeon and the procedure. The Brazilian Butt Lift costs less than other types of body contouring surgery because there is less fat grafting needed to get results that look natural.</p>



<p>Buttock Augmentation Cost</p>



<p>The Buttock Augmentation Cost is $2,500 to $3,500 per buttock (both sides). The cost will vary depending on the surgeon and the procedure. The Buttock Augmentation costs less than other types of body contouring surgery because there is less fat grafting needed for a natural-looking result</p>



<p>The Brazilian Tummy Tuck cost is dependent on a number of factors, including the type of procedure you choose and how much your medical insurance will cover.</p>



<p>The average Brazilian Tummy Tuck price is $5,500. This figure includes the surgeon fee, anesthesia fee, and hospital or surgical center fee.</p>



<p>Some surgeons may charge more than this average because their experience level is higher or because they practice in an area with higher costs of living. Other surgeons may charge less than average because they have a lower-than-average operating room fees or because they offer discounts for paying in full within a certain timeframe after surgery.</p>



<p>If your insurance covers plastic surgery, you may be responsible for paying only your portion of the deductible (typically $100-$200) and coinsurance (typically 20%-35%). If your insurance does not cover plastic surgery, then you may be responsible for paying the entire cost of your procedure up front before undergoing any work at all.</p>



<p>The cost of a Brazilian Tummy Tuck will depend on a variety of factors such as experience of the surgeon and the complexity of the procedure. A typical tummy tuck surgery will cost between £6000 and £8000. The price may vary depending on whether you choose to have general anaesthetic or local anaesthetic.</p>



<p>Before undergoing surgery, you should ask your surgeon how much they charge for the procedure and how many operations they perform each year. This will give you an idea of the quality of their work and whether or not they are experienced enough to perform your surgery.</p>



<p>The cost can also vary depending on whether you choose to have general anaesthetic or local anaesthetic. You should also factor in travel expenses if your surgeon is located far away from where you live</p><p>The post <a href="/2023/03/22/brazil-tummy-tuck-prices/">Brazil Tummy Tuck Prices</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2023/03/22/brazil-tummy-tuck-prices/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Brazilian Buttock Lift And Tummy Tuck Cost</title>
		<link>/2023/03/22/brazilian-buttock-lift-and-tummy-tuck-cost/</link>
					<comments>/2023/03/22/brazilian-buttock-lift-and-tummy-tuck-cost/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Ajay Emancipate]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 11:37:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tummy Tuck]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cosmeticsenvogue.com/?p=11082</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Both are designed to improve your body&#8217;s contours by removing excess fat and skin, but they differ in how much skin is removed. A Brazilian buttock lift removes fat and skin from your upper inner and outer buttocks and tightens the muscles beneath. A tummy tuck removes fat from your abdomen and tightens the muscles...</p>
<p>The post <a href="/2023/03/22/brazilian-buttock-lift-and-tummy-tuck-cost/">Brazilian Buttock Lift And Tummy Tuck Cost</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Both are designed to improve your body&#8217;s contours by removing excess fat and skin, but they differ in how much skin is removed. A Brazilian buttock lift removes fat and skin from your upper inner and outer buttocks and tightens the muscles beneath. A tummy tuck removes fat from your abdomen and tightens the muscles under your abdomen.</p>



<p>The cost of these surgeries varies based on where you live—and what type of insurance coverage you have. Your doctor will be able to give you an estimate after reviewing your medical history and answering questions about your lifestyle habits like smoking or drinking alcohol regularly (both of which can increase recovery time after surgery).</p>



<p> Read on to learn more about Brazilian Buttock Lift And Tummy Tuck Cost, How To Prepare For Your Procedure Abroad AND How much does tummy tuck cost</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" src="https://cosmeticsurgerytips.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/image-1230.png" alt="" class="wp-image-124220" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Brazilian Buttock Lift And Tummy Tuck Cost</h2>



<p>The cost of a butt surgery is an important consideration among most patients planning cosmetic surgery to enhance their contour and acquire a fuller, rounder, sexier derriere. However, unlike other plastic surgery procedures, a butt augmentation is the most surgeon-dependent one. Of course, it goes without saying that you do need to find elite plastic surgeons with stellar credentials and a wealth of experience in the particular cosmetic surgery procedure so that you can ensure optimal results. This is one of the most distinct cases when cheap and quality do not go hand-in-hand. It is important to understand that your budget can indeed affect the outcome so it is strongly advised to balance a lower price tag with other factors, such as the doctor&#8217;s training and experience, before making a final decision.</p>



<p>Brazilian Butt Lift Cost</p>



<p>The cost of a Brazilian butt lift varies widely, depending on the surgeon&#8217;s fee, hospital costs and the type of implant used. The average price for this procedure is about $4,000 to $5,000 per cheek (for 1,000 cc to 2,000 cc of silicone gel). As with many other cosmetic surgery procedures, you can expect to pay more if you have more extensive work done (e.g., implants in both buttocks).</p>



<p>Tummy Tuck Cost</p>



<p>Tummy tucks can range from $8,500 to $20,000 or more depending on where you live and the extent of your surgery. If your surgeon uses a tummy tuck seen as an elective procedure by insurance companies — meaning that they don&#8217;t consider it an essential treatment — then your out-of-pocket cost could be even higher than those quoted above. According to The American Society for Aesthetic Plastic Surgery (ASAPS), total spending on cosmetic procedures in 2011 was $11 billion; however, only about half of these procedures were covered by health insurance plans.</p>



<p>Brazilian Buttock Lift And Tummy Tuck Cost</p>



<p>The average cost of a Brazilian butt lift and tummy tuck ranges from $8,000 to $15,000. The cost varies greatly based on the surgeon&#8217;s experience, geographic location and the type of procedure performed.</p>



<p>Brazilian Butt Lift And Tummy Tuck Prices</p>



<p>The cost of your Brazilian butt lift and tummy tuck will depend on several factors including:</p>



<p>Surgeon&#8217;s experience &#8211; An experienced surgeon can perform a Brazilian butt lift with less risk of complications or side effects than an inexperienced surgeon.</p>



<p>Geographic location &#8211; Surgeons located in major metropolitan areas tend to charge more than surgeons in rural areas.</p>



<p>Type of procedure performed &#8211; Procedures that require more complex techniques or procedures will generally have higher prices than those that are less complicated.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="LIVE SURGERY | Brazilian Butt Lift (BBL) | Tummy Tuck in San Francisco-Part 1of 5 Interview &amp; Pre-Op" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rjXjgKT_odU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How To Prepare For Your Procedure Abroad</h2>



<p>To prepare for your procedure, it is best to talk to the surgeon who will be treating you. He or she will be able to give you all of the details you need to know when it comes to how to prep for what lies ahead, as well as what steps you need to take to recover perfectly.<br><br>After you have booked your surgery and you know how much time you will be staying in the facility for prep, surgery, and recuperation, you can make your travel arrangements. If you are going to a non-English speaking facility, take a translator with you. Be sure your passport is valid for 6 months beyond your travel date, purchase your plane tickets, and book your accommodations in advance. And don’t forget to discuss how you will pay for the surgery, as some facilities will allow you to pay in instalments, while others may want you to pay for everything upfront.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://www.ofx.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/image-71.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-4332" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Smart ways to pay for your plastic surgery abroad</h2>



<p>Check with your health insurance provider to determine if any of the costs of your plastic surgery abroad will be covered. If not, you will need to determine how much you can pay out of pocket, or you can ask about international medical coverage, which is becoming more common, thanks to the rise in popularity of medical tourism.<br><br>Services like OFX also make it easy to submit payments internationally from your bank account. Your currency will be converted, and your transfer can be completed online and tracked with a convenient mobile app. And by using OFX, you can save even more money when it comes to having your currency converted and sent abroad (bye-bye, bank fees and hefty margins!), leaving more of your budget available for travel and medical costs. Plus, you can opt to use a&nbsp;Forward Contract&nbsp;to lock in a great exchange rate for up to one year in order to protect yourself from foreign exchange volatility as you pay for your surgery.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Taking the leap towards looking your best&nbsp;</h3>



<p>People go abroad for a lot of things, like school, health care, employment, and retirement. So it is really no surprise that getting plastic surgery in another country is quite popular amongst individuals who want to get high quality care at a more affordable price.</p>



<p>By following the right strategy for not only finding the best surgeon, but also paying for your procedure, you can take the leap towards looking your best and perfecting whatever flaws you no longer want to deal with. Before you know it, you will be flaunting your new look and loving the confidence that you have gained.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How much does tummy tuck cost</h2>



<p>A&nbsp;tummy tuck&nbsp;is a procedure that tightens the loose, sagging skin between your belly button and the pubic area. However, the scope of the process might vary, depending on your needs and preference. If you’ve ever considered the procedure, you’ve probably asked yourself, “how much does a mini tummy tuck cost?”<strong>‌</strong></p>



<p>According to the American Society of Plastic Surgeons, the average cost of a mini tummy tuck stood at $6,092 in 2019. However, with the increasing cost of living, everything seems to be getting more expensive. &nbsp;It’s therefore likely that this figure has increased in the past few months. There are also additional expenses that come with the procedure. This puts the cost in the range of $3,000 to $15,000. You should consider these fees and expenses when researching a tummy tuck.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="091e9c5e821d5a0a-1-2">What is a Mini Tummy Tuck?</h2>



<p>A tummy tuck, also known as abdominoplasty, refers to a surgical procedure that alters the&nbsp;abdominal&nbsp;skin, soft tissues, and fat. It doesn’t affect the abdominal muscles. Tummy tucks are used for the lower abdomen and also to contour the body into the desired shape. The procedure is ideal for people within their recommended weight range but who have an extra layer of skin or fat that they need to address.<strong>‌</strong></p>



<p>During the procedure, the specialist attending to you joins the tissues in your lower abdomen together. The results of the surgery are not visible from the outside. They also trim the excess skin and lay it flat. Depending on how much fat is in the area, the specialist will also perform&nbsp;liposuction&nbsp;to remove any excess fat.<strong>‌</strong></p>



<p>In some cases, a mini tummy tuck can get rid of certain&nbsp;stretch marks. However, their removal depends on their placement on your body and how much excess skin you have.<strong>‌</strong></p>



<p>In cases of&nbsp;diastasis recti, which is the separation of&nbsp;ab muscles, a full tummy tuck is a better option. The condition mostly happens during pregnancy, affecting the entire area above and below the&nbsp;navel.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="091e9c5e821d5a0a-1-4">What Affects the Cost of a Tummy Tuck?</h2>



<p>Many factors come into play when determining the cost of a tummy tuck.<strong>‌</strong></p>



<p><strong>The extent of the procedure.</strong>&nbsp;In some cases, all that is involved in a tummy tuck is tightening the loose, sagging skin below the navel. However, the process is customizable to meet your needs and preferences. Depending on how much work the surgeon has to do, the procedure can either be a full, mini, or extended tummy tuck.&nbsp;<strong>‌</strong></p>



<p>A mini tummy tuck that only addresses the loose skin may cost between $4,000 and $5,000. A traditional tummy tuck may cost between $8,000 and $10,000, while an extended tummy job may be worth up to $20,000.<strong>‌</strong></p>



<p><strong>The size of the area.</strong>&nbsp;If the procedure only entails tightening loose skin and eliminating fat from the lower abdomen, the cost will be relatively low. However, when you need a full tummy tuck, the procedure’s scope calls for more expenses. This is because it involves both the upper and lower abdomen. Extended tummy tucks are also more expensive because they involve the front side, back, and sides.</p>



<p><strong>The volume of fat removed.</strong>&nbsp;The extent of the procedure can be fat removal, muscle tightening, skin lifting and tightening, and muscle reshaping or repairing. The more services you get during the process, the higher the cost will be.</p>



<p><strong>The type of anesthesia used.</strong>&nbsp;The type and dosage of anesthesia you receive during a tummy tuck is another significant factor that affects the procedure’s cost. If you require a larger dose of anesthesia depending on the extent of the surgery, the price will be higher.&nbsp;</p>



<p>General anesthesia is usually more expensive than local anesthesia. The reason for this is that with local anesthesia, you may also have to take a sedative to help you sleep through the procedure, hence a lower dose. The cost of general anesthesia is between $425 and $1,800, while that of local anesthesia is between $500 and $3,500.</p>



<p><strong>The number of procedures to be performed.</strong>&nbsp;In some cases, lifting and tightening your stomach skin is not enough to help you achieve your ideal aesthetic level. As such, you may be a good candidate for an extra procedure. Doing so will help to contour your body by removing excess fat. Liposuction is usually an ideal complementary procedure to tummy tuck as it draws more fat than a tummy tuck.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="091e9c5e821d5a0a-3-8">Preparing for a Tummy Tuck</h2>



<p>Before you go in for a tummy tuck, your doctor may schedule you for a blood panel to ensure you’re in good health. You will also be required to:</p>



<ul>
<li>Stop&nbsp;smoking</li>



<li>Limit your alcohol intake</li>



<li>Stop taking&nbsp;anti-inflammatory drugs&nbsp;and some herbal supplements that can make bleeding worse or hinder clotting.</li>
</ul><p>The post <a href="/2023/03/22/brazilian-buttock-lift-and-tummy-tuck-cost/">Brazilian Buttock Lift And Tummy Tuck Cost</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2023/03/22/brazilian-buttock-lift-and-tummy-tuck-cost/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Brazilian Tummy Tuck Cost Uk</title>
		<link>/2023/03/22/brazilian-tummy-tuck-cost-uk/</link>
					<comments>/2023/03/22/brazilian-tummy-tuck-cost-uk/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Emma Ajay Emancipate]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 11:33:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tummy Tuck]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cosmeticsenvogue.com/?p=11084</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Tummy tucks are commonly performed to improve the appearance of loose skin and excess fat in the abdominal area, as well as to tighten weakened or separated muscles after pregnancy. In some cases, a tummy tuck can also correct medical problems such as hernias and rectal prolapse. Before and After Photos These photos show what...</p>
<p>The post <a href="/2023/03/22/brazilian-tummy-tuck-cost-uk/">Brazilian Tummy Tuck Cost Uk</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tummy tucks are commonly performed to improve the appearance of loose skin and excess fat in the abdominal area, as well as to tighten weakened or separated muscles after pregnancy. In some cases, a tummy tuck can also correct medical problems such as hernias and rectal prolapse.</p>



<p>Before and After Photos These photos show what a Brazilian tummy tuck can do for your body. The results may vary from person to person due to factors like age and other medical conditions. To learn more about Brazilian tummy tuck cost uk, contact us today.</p>



<p>Read on to learn more about Brazilian Tummy Tuck Cost Uk, How To Compare The Cost Of Plastic Surgery Abroad and How To Avoid Common Risks That Come With Undergoing Plastic Surgery</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://cosmeticsurgerytips.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/image-538.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-11220" width="642" height="503" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Brazilian Tummy Tuck Cost Uk</h2>



<p>Abdominoplasty, more commonly known as a ‘tummy tuck’, is a surgical procedure which sees excess skin removed from the waist and the tightening of the muscles and fascia of the abdominal wall to achieve a tighter, flatter-looking stomach.</p>



<p>Tummy tucks are very popular, making up one in five of all the cosmetic surgery procedures carried out in the UK.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Abdominoplasty is an effective way of getting rid of excess, slack skin, often left behind after significant weight loss. Excess fat causes our skin to stretch and when this weight is lost, the skin is not able to retract back to its original state. As we age, our bodies produce less collagen, meaning the skin loses its elasticity, making it more prone to wrinkles and sagging. This means that even a more modest amount of weight loss can leave sagging skin behind, particularly in older people with less collagen.Get in touchPlay</p>



<p>Women are often left with surplus skin and slack, weakened stomach muscles following pregnancy and C-sections, meaning tummy tucks are a popular way to help restore the body back to its pre-childbirth state.</p>



<p>Abdominoplasty is often combined with other treatments such as liposuction and body contouring treatments such as breast augmentation. Our ‘mummy makeover’, a combination of surgeries involving the breast, abdomen, waist, hips and thighs designed to restore the body to its original contours, is particularly popular with women who have given birth.</p>



<ul>
<li>Abdominoplasty delivers very long lasting results, but it is important you take care of your new body to ensure its longevity. You should maintain a stable weight, avoiding dramatic weight fluctuations. If you are planning another pregnancy, we would advise waiting until you have completed your family.</li>
</ul>



<p>The Brazilian Tummy Tuck cost is dependent on a number of factors, including the type of procedure you choose and how much your medical insurance will cover.</p>



<p>The average Brazilian Tummy Tuck price is $5,500. This figure includes the surgeon fee, anesthesia fee, and hospital or surgical center fee.</p>



<p>Some surgeons may charge more than this average because their experience level is higher or because they practice in an area with higher costs of living. Other surgeons may charge less than average because they have a lower-than-average operating room fees or because they offer discounts for paying in full within a certain timeframe after surgery.</p>



<p>If your insurance covers plastic surgery, you may be responsible for paying only your portion of the deductible (typically $100-$200) and coinsurance (typically 20%-35%). If your insurance does not cover plastic surgery, then you may be responsible for paying the entire cost of your procedure up front before undergoing any work at all.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Tummy Tuck 4 Month Update | Ups &amp; Downs, Is It Worth It?" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/k2oJLTli_WI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p></p>



<p></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How To Compare The Cost Of Plastic Surgery Abroad</h2>



<p>Comparing the cost of plastic surgery in another country can be a bit challenging, as you will need to consider exchange rate fluctuations when pricing your procedures. But on top of that, you should also calculate the total cost of having your procedure completed abroad. So, in addition to the actual cost of the surgery, also enquire about various other costs that you will be responsible for, such as:</p>



<ul>
<li>Pre-op and post-op consultation fees</li>



<li>Lab work costs</li>



<li>Medication costs</li>



<li>Anaesthesia costs</li>



<li>Aftercare fees</li>



<li>Facility and surgeon fees</li>



<li>Miscellaneous fees that depend upon your surgery, such as compression garments or breast implants</li>
</ul>



<p>Also, because you will be travelling abroad, you will need to factor in the cost of getting to and from your destination, as well as the cost of accommodations and transportation while you are there.<br><br>Different countries will charge different amounts of money for the same procedure, and this could help you narrow down your choices to the right destination for your needs. For example, while a rhinoplasty will cost a little over $400 USD in Thailand, it will cost over $1,000 USD in Malaysia. Breast implants, on the other hand, could cost around $1,800 USD in Brazil, or around $2,600 in Thailand.<br><br>Compare those prices with the United States, where the average cost of a rhinoplasty could be around $5,000 USD, while breast augmentation can be around $3,700 USD.&nbsp;Rhinoplasty in Australia could cost around $8,000 AUD, while breast implants could cost around $10,000 AUD.&nbsp;Breast implants in the United Kingdom could cost around £3,500 to £7,000, while a rhinoplasty could average anywhere from £4,500 to £7,000.<br><br>These costs are averages, and they can change at any time. They also may not include the extra fees associated with having a procedure, and they do not include personal travel costs.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://www.ofx.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/image-70.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-4331" /></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How To Avoid Common Risks That Come With Undergoing Plastic Surgery</h2>



<p>As is the case when undergoing any type of surgery, whether at home or abroad, there are certain risks involved. Knowing the surgical procedure and what you should expect before, during, and after will help you fully prepare for what lies ahead and take appropriate precautions to avoid complications.<br><br>Finding the right surgeon and medical facility abroad will also help ensure that your treatment will be top-notch. Ask plenty of questions, ask to see accreditations and certifications, look into patient referrals and read reviews, and make sure all of the costs are laid out so you will know how to budget appropriately.<br><br>Choosing a facility that has medical professionals who speak English will also help reduce the risk of problems arising from miscommunications and misunderstandings that can result from language barriers and improper translations.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How to prepare for your procedure abroad</h2>



<ul>
<li>To prepare for your procedure, it is best to talk to the surgeon who will be treating you. He or she will be able to give you all of the details you need to know when it comes to how to prep for what lies ahead, as well as what steps you need to take to recover perfectly.</li>



<li></li>



<li>After you have booked your surgery and you know how much time you will be staying in the facility for prep, surgery, and recuperation, you can make your travel arrangements. If you are going to a non-English speaking facility, take a translator with you. Be sure your passport is valid for 6 months beyond your travel date, purchase your plane tickets, and book your accommodations in advance. And don’t forget to discuss how you will pay for the surgery, as some facilities will allow you to pay in instalments, while others may want you to pay for everything upfront.&nbsp;</li>



<li></li>
</ul><p>The post <a href="/2023/03/22/brazilian-tummy-tuck-cost-uk/">Brazilian Tummy Tuck Cost Uk</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Blog</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2023/03/22/brazilian-tummy-tuck-cost-uk/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!--
Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: https://www.boldgrid.com/w3-total-cache/

Object Caching 84/102 objects using apc
Page Caching using apc (Requested URI contains query) 
Database Caching 17/21 queries in 0.049 seconds using apc

Served from: cosmeticsenvogue.eclipse1803.com @ 2023-04-07 14:11:45 by W3 Total Cache
-->